<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>productivityhack &#8211; Andy Pande</title>
	<atom:link href="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/tag/productivityhack/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/</link>
	<description>Web Development Enthusiast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 04:55:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Getting Shit Done for professional procrastinators</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/06/21/getting-shit-done-for-professional-procrastinators/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/06/21/getting-shit-done-for-professional-procrastinators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 04:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getshitdone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gettingshitdone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifehack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pomodori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pomodoritechnique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivityhack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workmanagement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=80</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever felt the feeling of leaving work with an uneasy feeling in your stomach that you are surely...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever felt the feeling of leaving work with an uneasy feeling in your stomach that you are surely forgetting something on your to-do list but your brain is too fried and distracted to remember it? So have I, very frequently, up till recently when I came across a foolproof way to get all your tasks done at work AND keep your mind organized and sane.</p>
<p>The productivity hack is called The Pomodoro Technique.</p>
<p>If you are not familiar with the technique, the jist of it is as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Work in 25 minute increments</li>
<li>5 minutes of break time after 25 minute work</li>
<li>DO NOT end a pomodori early – if you finish the task with time to spare, review your notes or see if you can enhance the task in any way possible</li>
<li>DO NOT check email during a pomodori – only focused work during this time. How hard is it to work for 25 minutes anyways – a break is coming right after</li>
<li>Mandatory that you take a 5 minute break after each pomodori and a 15 minute break after a set of 4 pomodori &#8211; feel free to check email during this break</li>
<li>If any idea comes up to distract pomodori, simply jot it down and get back to task at hand</li>
<li>Review idea post pomodori completion and add it to To-Do list if still important</li>
<li>If something can be completed under 2 mins, just do it now. Otherwise write it down</li>
<li>If anyone comes by to discuss during Pomodoro, just tell them you’ll get back with them in time after this Pomodoro ends &#8211; no one will get upset by having to wait less than a half hour. This one is really important &#8211; Do not be afraid to say you will get back to them shortly.</li>
</ul>
<p>The way I setup my pomodori list is on a note on my desktop. At the top of the note, I have the rules you see above and below the rules I keep a list of my tasks. Each day starts with looking over these tasks and ensuring the right tasks are on the list for the day and estimating how many 25 minute work increments it will take to complete each task. Each day will be different based on meetings and obligations so I would recommend slicing up the rest of the leftover hours of the day into 25 minute increments and that is how many Pomodori&#8217;s you have to work with. A screenshot of my desktop monitor looks like this: <img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-81" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/image.png" alt="image" width="1600" height="900" /></p>
<p>Anyone can concentrate for 25 minutes at a time, and more often than not, before hitting that 25 minute mark, you will be in a flow state on your current task and can take the 5 minute break to catch up on emails before getting excited for the 25 minute buzzer to sound again so you can get back into the flow.</p>
<p>Since implementing this technique into my daily workday, I have seen my productivity skyrocket and I no longer feel overwhelmed or anxious on a daily basis as was the norm previously. I have also noticed caffeine consumption drop considerably on a daily basis but focus is greatly increased.</p>
<p>Bonus: Chrome has a fantastic plugin for tracking your pomodoro cycles and I highly recommend you use it: https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/marinara-pomodoro%C2%AE-assist/lojgmehidjdhhbmpjfamhpkpodfcodef?utm_source=gmail</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/06/21/getting-shit-done-for-professional-procrastinators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
