<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pande Saab &#8211; Andy Pande</title>
	<atom:link href="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/author/andypande/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/</link>
	<description>Web Development Enthusiast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:57:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Best Summary for How to Invest without Emotions</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/14/the-best-summary-for-how-to-invest-without-emotions/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/14/the-best-summary-for-how-to-invest-without-emotions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benjamin graham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intelligent investor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the intelligent investor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=100</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This blog post is just an excerpt from the legendary Investing book &#8211; The Intelligent Investor &#8211; but it is...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This blog post is just an excerpt from the legendary Investing book &#8211; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Intelligent-Investor-Collins-Business-Essentials-ebook/dp/B000FC12C8">The Intelligent Investor</a> &#8211; but it is by far the best and most entertaining summary I have ever read on how to handle the market fluctuations without emotion and how to be rational in an irrational world. Without further ado, here&#8217;s the excerpt from the book in it&#8217;s entirety:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Most of the time, the market is mostly accurate in pricing most stocks. Millions of buyers and sellers haggling over price do a remarkably good job of valuing companies &#8211; on average. But sometimes, the price is not right, occasionally, it is very wrong indeed. And at such times, you need to understand the image of Mr. Market, probably the most brilliant metaphor ever created for explaining how stocks can be mis-priced. The manic depressive Mr. Market does not always price stocks the way an appraiser or a private buyer would value a business. Instead, when stocks are going up, he happily pays more than the objective value; and, when they are going down, he is desperate to dump them for less than their true worth. </span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Is Mr. Market still around? Is he still bipolar? You bet he is.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">On March 17, 2000, the stock of Inktomi Corp. hit a new high of $231.62. Since they first came on the market in June 1998, shares in the Internet-searching software company had gained roughly 1900%. Just in the few weeks since December 1999, the stock had nearly tripled. </span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">What was going on at Inktomi that could make the stock so valuable? The answer seems obvious: phenomenally fast growth. In the three months ending in December 1999, Inktomi sold $36 million in products and services, more than it had in the entire year ending in December 1998. If Inktomi could sustain its growth rate of the previous 12 months for just five more years, its revenues would explore from $36 million a quarter to $5 billion a month. With such growth in sight, the faster the stock went up, the farther up it seemed certain to go.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">But in his wild love affair with Inktomi’s stock, Mr. Market was overlooking something about its business. The company was losing money &#8211; lots of it. It had lost $6 million in the most recent quarter, $24 million in the 12 months before that, and $24 million in the year before that. In its entire corporate lifetime, Inktomi had never made a dime in profits. Yet, on March 17, 2000, Mr. Market valued this business at a total of $25 billion (Yes, that’s billion, with a B.)</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">And then Mr. Market went into a sudden, nightmarish depression. On September 30, 2002, just two and a half years after hitting $231.62 per share, Inktomi’s stock closed at 25 cents &#8211; collapsing from a total market value of $25 billion to less than $40 million. Had Inktomi’s business dried up? Not at all; over the previous 12 months, the company had generated $113 million in revenues. So what had changed? Only Mr. Market’s mood: In early 2000, investors were so wild about the Internet that they priced Inktomi’s shares at 250 times the company’s revenues. Now, however, they would pay only 0.35 times its revenues. Mr. Market had morphed from Dr. Jekyll to Mr. Hyde and was ferociously trashing every stock that had made a fool of him.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">But Mr. Market was no more justified in his midnight rage than he had been in his manic euphoria. On December 23, 2002, Yahoo announced that it would buy Inktomi for $1.65 a share. That was nearly seven times Inktomi’s stock price on September 30. History will probably show that Yahoo got a bargain. When Mr. Market makes stocks so cheap, it’s no wonder that entire companies get bought right out from under him.</span></p>
<p class="" style="text-align:center;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Think for Yourself</span></span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Would you willingly allow a certifiable lunatic to come by at least five times a week to tell you that you should feel exactly the way he feels? Would you ever agree to be euphoric just because he is &#8211; or miserable just because he thinks you should be? Of course not. You’d insist on your right to take control of your own emotional life, based on your experiences and your beliefs. But, when it comes to their financial lives, millions of people let Mr. Market tell them how to feel and what to do &#8211; despite the obvious fact that, from time to time, he can get nuttier than a fruitcake. </span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">In 1999, when Mr. Market was squealing with delight, American employees directed an average of 8.6% of their pay checks into their 401(k) retirement plans. By 2002, after Mr. Market had spent three years stuffing stocks into black garbage bags, the average contribution rate had dropped by nearly one quarter, to just 7%. The cheaper stocks got, the less eager people became to buy them &#8211; because they were imitating Mr. Market, instead of thinking for themselves.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">The intelligent investor shouldn’t ignore Mr. Market entirely. Instead, you should do business with him &#8211; but only to the extent that it serves your interests. Mr. Market’s job is to provide you with prices; your job is to decide whether it is your advantage to act on them. You do not have to trade with him just because he constantly begs you to.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">By refusing to let Mr. Market be your master, you transform him into your servant. After all, even when he seems to be destroying values, he is creating them elsewhere. In 1999, the Wilshire 5000 index &#8211; the broadest measure of U.S stock performance &#8211; gained 23.8%, powered by technology and telecommunications stocks. But 3743 of 7324 stocks in the Wilshire index went down in value as the average was rising. While those high tech and telecom stocks were hotter than the hood of a race car on an August afternoon, thousands of “Old Economy” shares were frozen in the mud &#8211; getting cheaper and cheaper. </span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">The stock of CMGI, an “incubator” or holding company for Internet start-up firms, went up an astonishing 939.9% in 1999. Meanwhile, Berkshire Hathaway &#8211; the holding company through which Graham’s greatest disciple, Warrant Buffet, owns such Old Economy stalwarts as Coca-Cola, Gillette, and the Washington Post Co &#8211; dropped by 24.9%. But then, as it so often goes, the market had a sudden mood swing. As for those two holding companies, CMGI went on to lose 96% in 2000, another 70.9% in 2001, and still 39.8% more in 2002 &#8211; a cumulative loss of 99.3%. Berkshire Hathaway went up to 26.6% in 2000 and 6.5% in 2001, then had a slight 3.8% loss in 2002 &#8211; a cumulative gain of 30%. </span></p>
<p class="" style="text-align:center;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Can You Beat the Pros at Their Own Game?</span></span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">One of Graham’s most powerful insights is this: “The investor who permits himself to be stampeded or unduly worried by unjustified marked declines in his holdings is perversely transforming his basic advantage into a basic disadvantage.”</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">What does Graham mean by those words “basic advantage”? He means that the intelligent individual investor has the full freedom to choose where or not to follow Mr. Market. You have the luxury of being able to think for yourself.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">The typical money manager, however, has no choice but to mimic Mr. Market’s every move &#8211; buying high, selling low, marking almost mindlessly in his erratic footsteps. Here are some of the handicaps mutual-fund managers and other professional investors are saddled with:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">With billions of dollars under management, they must gravitate toward the biggest stocks. The only ones they can buy in the multimillion-dollar quantities they need to fill their portfolios. Thus many funds end up owning the same few overpriced giants.</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Investors tend to pour more money into the funds as the market rises. The managers use that new cash to buy more of the stocks they already own, driving prices to even more dangerous heights.</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">If fund investors ask for their money back when the market drops, the managers may need to sell stocks to cash them out. Just as the funds are forced to buy stocks at inflated prices in a rising market, they become forced seller as stocks get cheap again.</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Many portfolio managers get bonuses for beating the market, so they obsessively measure their returns against benchmarks like the S&amp;P 500. If a company gets added to an index, hundreds of funds compulsively buy it. (If they don’t, and that stock then does well, the managers look foolish; on the other hand, if they buy it and it does poorly, no one will blame them.)</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Increasingly, fund managers are expected to specialize. Just as in medicine the general practitioner has given way to the pediatric allergist and the geriatric otolaryngologist, fund managers must buy only “small growth” stocks, or only “mid-sized value” stocks, or nothing but “large blend” stocks. If a company gets too big, or too small, or too cheap, or an itty bit too expensive, the fund has to sell it &#8211; even if the manager loves the stock.</span></li>
</ul>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">So there’s no reason you can’t do as well as the pros. What you cannot do (despite all the pundits who say you can) is to “beat the pros at their own game.” The pros can’t even win their own game! Why should you want to play it at all? If you follow their rules, you will lose &#8211; since you will end up as much a slave to Mr. Market as the professionals are.</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Instead, recognize that investing intelligently is about controlling the controllable. You can’t control whether the stocks or funds you buy will outperform the market today, next week, this month, or this year; in the short run, your returns will always be hostage to Mr. Market and his whims. But you can control:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">your brokerage costs, by trading rarely, patiently, and cheaply</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">your ownership costs, by refusing to buy mutual funds with excessive annual expenses</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">your expectations, by using realism, not fantasy, to forecast your returns</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">your risk, by deciding how much of your total asset to put at hazard in the stock market, by diversifying, and by rebalancing</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">your tax bills, by holding stocks for at least one year and, whenever possible, for at least five years, to lower your capital-gains liability</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">and, most of all, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">YOUR OWN BEHAVIOR</span></span></li>
</ul>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">If you listen to financial TV, or read most market columnists, you’d think that investing is some kind of sport, or a war, or a struggle for survival in a hostile wilderness. <strong>But investing isn’t about beating others at their game. It’s about controlling yourself at your own game.</strong> The challenge for the intelligent investor is not to find the stocks that will go up the most and down the least, but rather to prevent yourself from being your own worst enemy—from buying high just because Mr. Market says “Buy!” and from selling low just because Mr. Market says “Sell!</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">If your investment horizon is long—at least 25 or 30 years—there is only one sensible approach: Buy every month, automatically, and whenever else you can spare some money. The single best choice for this lifelong holding is a total stock-market index fund. Sell only when you need the cash (for a psychological boost, clip out and sign your “Investment Owner’s Contract” &#8211; found at the end of this blog post)</span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">To be an intelligent investor, you must also refuse to judge your financial success by how a bunch of total strangers are doing. You’re not one penny poorer if someone in Dubuque or Dallas or Denver beats the S&amp;P 500 and you don’t. No one’s gravestone reads “HE BEAT THE MARKET.” I once interviewed a group of retirees in Boca Raton, one of Florida’s wealthiest retirement communities. I asked these people—mostly in their seventies—if they had beaten the market over their investing lifetimes. Some said yes, some said no; most weren’t sure. Then one man said, “Who cares? All I know is, my investments earned enough for me to end up in Boca.”Could there be a more perfect answer? After all, the whole point of investing is not to earn more money than average, but to earn enough money to meet your own needs. The best way to measure your investing success is not by whether you’re beating the market but by whether you’ve put in place a financial plan and a behavioral discipline that are likely to get you where you want to go. In the end, what matters isn’t crossing the finish line before anybody else but just making sure that you do cross it.</span></p>
<p class="" style="text-align:center;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Your Money and Your Brain</span></span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Why, then, do investors find Mr. Market so seductive? It turns out that our brains are hardwired to get us into investing trouble; humans are pattern-seeking animals. Psychologists have shown that if you present people with a random sequence—and tell them that it’s unpredictable—they will nevertheless insist on trying to guess what’s coming next. Likewise, we “know” that the next roll of the dice will be a seven, that a baseball player is due for a base hit, that the next winning number in the Powerball lottery will definitely be 4-27-9-16-42-10—and that this hot little stock is the next Microsoft. Groundbreaking new research in neuroscience shows that our brains are designed to perceive trends even where they might not exist. After an event occurs just two or three times in a row, regions of the human brain called the anterior cingulate and nucleus accumbens automatically anticipate that it will happen again. If it does repeat, a natural chemical called dopamine is released, flooding your brain with a soft euphoria. Thus, if a stock goes up a few times in a row, you reflexively expect it to keep going—and your brain chemistry changes as the stock rises, giving you a “natural high.” You effectively become addicted to your own predictions. But when stocks drop, that financial loss fires up your amygdala—the part of the brain that processes fear and anxiety and generates the famous “fight or flight” response that is common to all cornered animals. Just as you can’t keep your heart rate from rising if a fire alarm goes off, just as you can’t avoid flinching if a rattlesnake slithers onto your hiking path, you can’t help feeling fearful when stock prices are plunging. In fact, the brilliant psychologists Daniel Kahneman and Amos Tversky have shown that the pain of financial loss is more than twice as intense as the pleasure of an equivalent gain. Making $1,000 on a stock feels great—but a $1,000 loss wields an emotional wallop more than twice as powerful. Losing money is so painful that many people, terrified at the prospect of any further loss, sell out near the bottom or refuse to buy more. That helps explain why we fixate on the raw magnitude of a market decline and forget to put the loss in proportion. So, if a TV reporter hollers, “The market is plunging—the Dow is down 100 points!” most people instinctively shudder. But, assuming the DOW level of 8,000, that’s a drop of just 1.2%. Now think how ridiculous it would sound if, on a day when it’s 81 degrees outside, the TV weatherman shrieked, “The temperature is plunging—it’s dropped from 81 degrees to 80 degrees!” That, too, is a 1.2% drop. When you forget to view changing market prices in percentage terms, it’s all too easy to panic over minor vibrations. In the late 1990s, many people came to feel that they were in the dark unless they checked the prices of their stocks several times a day. But, as Graham puts it, the typical investor “would be better off if his stocks had no market quotation at all, for he would then be spared the mental anguish caused him by other persons’ mistakes of judgment.” If, after checking the value of your stock portfolio at 1:24 P.M., you feel compelled to check it all over again at 1:37 P.M., ask yourself the questions 1-3 listed below: </span></p>
<ol>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Did I call a real-estate agent to check the market price of my house at 1:24 P.M.? Did I call back at 1:37 P.M.?</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">If I had, would the price have changed? If it did, would I have rushed to sell my house?</span></li>
<li><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">By not checking, or even knowing, the market price of my house from minute to minute, do I prevent its value from rising over time?</span></li>
</ol>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">The only possible answer to these questions is of course not! And you should view your portfolio the same way. Over a 10- or 20- or 30- year investment horizon, Mr. Market’s daily dipsy-doodles simply do not matter. In any case, for anyone who will be investing for years to come, falling stock prices are good news, not bad, since they enable you to buy more for less money. The longer and further stocks fall, and the more steadily you keep buying as they drop, the more money you will make in the end—if you remain steadfast until the end. Instead of fearing a bear market, you should embrace it. The intelligent investor should be perfectly comfortable owning a stock or mutual fund even if the stock market stopped supplying daily prices for the next 10 years. Paradoxically, “you will be much more in control,” explains neuroscientist Antonio Damasio, “if you realize how much you are not in control.” By acknowledging your biological tendency to buy high and sell low, you can admit the need to dollar-cost average, rebalance, and sign an investment contract. By putting much of your portfolio on permanent autopilot, you can fight the prediction addiction, focus on your long-term financial goals, and tune out Mr. Market’s mood swings.</span></p>
<p class="" style="text-align:center;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">NEWS YOU COULD USE</span></span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Stocks are crashing, so you turn on the television to catch the latest market news. But instead of CNBC or CNN, imagine that you can tune in to the Benjamin Graham Financial Network. On BGFN, the audio doesn’t capture that famous sour clang of the market’s closing bell; the video doesn’t home in on brokers scurrying across the floor of the stock exchange like angry rodents. Nor does BGFN run any footage of investors gasping on frozen sidewalks as red arrows whiz overhead on electronic stock tickers. Instead, the image that fills your TV screen is the facade of the New York Stock Exchange, festooned with a huge banner reading: “SALE! 50% OFF!” As intro music, Bachman-Turner Overdrive can be heard blaring a few bars of their old barn-burner, “You Ain’t Seen Nothin’ Yet.” Then the anchorman announces brightly, “Stocks became more attractive yet again today, as the Dow dropped another 2.5% on heavy volume—the fourth day in a row that stocks have gotten cheaper. Tech investors fared even better, as leading companies like Microsoft lost nearly 5% on the day, making them even more affordable. That comes on top of the good news of the past year, in which stocks have already lost 50%, putting them at bargain levels not seen in years. And some prominent analysts are optimistic that prices may drop still further in the weeks and months to come.”The newscast cuts over to market strategist Ignatz Anderson of the Wall Street firm of Ketchum &amp;  Skinner, who says, “My forecast is for stocks to lose another 15% by June. I’m cautiously optimistic that if everything goes well, stocks could lose 25%, maybe more.”“Let’s hope Ignatz Anderson is right,” the anchor says cheerily. “Falling stock prices would be fabulous news for any investor with a very long horizon. And now over to Wally Wood for our exclusive AccuWeather forecast.</span></p>
<p class="" style="text-align:center;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">When Mr. Market Gives You Lemons, Make Lemonade</span></span></p>
<p class=""><span class="" style="font-family:Helvetica Neue;font-size:medium;">Although Graham teaches that you should buy when Mr. Market is yelling “sell,” there’s one exception the intelligent investor needs to understand. Selling into a bear market can make sense if it creates a tax windfall. The U.S. Internal Revenue Code allows you to use your realized losses (any declines in value that you lock in by selling your shares) to offset up to $3,000 in ordinary income. Let’s say you bought 200 shares of Coca-Cola stock in January 2000 for $60 a share—a total investment of $12,000. By year-end 2002, the stock was down to $44 a share, or $8,800 for your lot—a loss of $3,200.You could have done what most people do—either whine about your loss, or sweep it under the rug and pretend it never happened. Or you could have taken control. Before 2002 ended, you could have sold all your Coke shares, locking in the $3,200 loss. Then, after waiting 31 days to comply with IRS rules, you would buy 200 shares of Coke all over again. The result: You would be able to reduce your taxable income by $3,000 in 2002, and you could use the remaining $200 loss to offset your income in 2003. And better yet, you would still own a company whose future you believe in—but now you would own it for almost one-third less than you paid the first time. With Uncle Sam subsidizing your losses, it can make sense to sell and lock in a loss. If Uncle Sam wants to make Mr. Market look logical by comparison, who are we to complain?</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>And as mentioned above, here is the investment owners contract that I highly recommend you download and sign and put into an easily visible place for yourself to view on a daily or weekly basis:</p>
<p><a title="Investment Owner Contract" href="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/investment-owner-contract.pdf">Investment Owner Contract</a></p>
<p>Thanks for Reading!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/14/the-best-summary-for-how-to-invest-without-emotions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore Solocation</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/02/singapore-solocation/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/02/singapore-solocation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 04:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=93</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just got back from a 4 day/4 night trip from Singapore and I am officially in love with this small...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Just got back from a 4 day/4 night trip from Singapore and I am officially in love with this small country in Southeast Asia. The first thing you notice in Singapore is just how clean and beautiful the country is. Next, you are blown away by the great diversity of the population and the tourists that are visiting the country. Driving through downtown on the way into the city, you cannot help but marvel at the majestic Marina Bay Sands, the Cloud Forest, the Singapore Flyer, and the SuperTree Grove. Pictures from Crazy Rich Asians flash in your head as you take in the immense wealth and potential the country holds. Immediately after visiting the country, I had to look up some history on how it has managed to prosper so well and I was shocked to find out that Singapore has only existed as an independent country for just over 50 years, only gaining independence in 1965! What’s even crazier is that the country has evolved from being a third world country when it was founded to a first world country in the matter of one generation, an astounding feat in itself. The country has also only had 3 prime ministers in it’s 54 years of independence and holds a one party meritocracy in it’s governing body.</p>
<p class="p1">My trip to Singapore was taken as a solo vacation &#8211; a solocation for short so I was hyper eager to soak in all the culture had to offer. Having grown up in India and visited a few countries in Southeast Asia, I have grown to expect a few surefire signs of being in Asia. In my mind upon arriving in Singapore, I expected there to be a homeless population easily visible even to tourists. Further, I expected there to be zero laws for drivers, and the make your own lane rule to govern how traffic flows. Finally, a subtle but noticeable fog/haziness was expected in the air from the pollution based on my previous experiences in Asia. Needless to say, none of this existed in Singapore. The homeless population is completely non-existent. Traffic flows without any honking and is managed beautifully. And the air, although very humid with up to 90% humidity, is very crisp and clean. Having stumped my beliefs of this actually being an Asian country, Singapore went above and beyond in blowing me away by just how safe it felt &#8211; even though I could not have looked any more like a tourist &#8211; by wearing a shirt with the Texas flag on it, an Astros ball cap and being glued to my phone for directions wherever I went, no part of Singapore felt unsafe. What was even cooler was how easy it was to use public transport in the city. On trip advisor, the number one rated attraction in Singapore is the Singapore Mass Rapid Transit (SMRT). Number one attraction in a city that holds the super tree grove, cloud forest, Marina Bay sands had me somewhat bewildered but after riding the train everywhere in the city for just 1-2 Singapore dollars per ride, I can see why it’s the best rated tourist attraction in the whole country.</p>
<p class="p1">My Singapore Solocation was split into two parts &#8211; part one was taking in the glitz and glamour of the country. This part consisted of trying delicious noms at the renowned Birds of a Feather restaurant. Next, I couldn’t leave the country without trying out some of the absolutely incredible cocktail bars. Operation Dagger was the first watering hole I visited where the bartenders made the most unique variation of an old fashioned that I have ever tried &#8211; this drink contained bee pollen and a dark chocolate twig. The bartenders could not have been nicer here and they hooked me up with a list of restaurants and other cocktail bars in the city to check out. Next on the treat yo self tour was checking out bar Manhattan in the Regent hotel. This bar is rated the best bar in Asia and the 3rd best bar in the world as of 2019 and boy did it ever hold up to that billing. The New York Sour was decadent and delicious, the waitstaff exemplary, and the ambiance and setting of the bar second to none. Having spent all of my next month’s pay check schmoozing, the 2nd part of my solocation involved checking out the more locals side of the country &#8211; and this part was even more delicious.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>New York Sour at the 3rd best bar in the world:</strong></span><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-96" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/unadjustednonraw_thumb_15c5.jpg" alt="UNADJUSTEDNONRAW_thumb_15c5.jpg" width="665" height="1182" /></p>
<p class="p1">While you can spend your whole vacation in Singapore visiting the top rated sites on Trip Advisor, you will be doing yourself a huge dis-service if you leave here without trying out the dozens of food hawker centers littered around the country. These hawker centers will get you a plate of authentic local food for under 5 Singapore Dollars. Plus, all varieties of food from Singaporean Laksa, to Malay dishes, to authentic Chinese food, to Indian delicacies to the most pungent but tasty desserts in South Asia made with Dorian can be bought for just a few dollars each. This was by far my favourite part of Singapore as the spices, flavours, ad aromas of these hawker centers were second to none &#8211; and my belly could not have been happier from the experience. There are some more touristy hawker centers like Newton food center that was depicted in Crazy Rich Asians and some more local friendly and tasty centers like the Maxwell food center but my list of the must try Hawker centers Food Recommendations are listed here:</p>
<p>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Trips/85571776</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>The original Katong Laksa &#8211; Absolute Must Try</strong></span><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-97" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/unadjustednonraw_thumb_15a4.jpg" alt="UNADJUSTEDNONRAW_thumb_15a4.jpg" width="768" height="1024" /></p>
<p class="p1">That about covers my overview of an unforgettable solocation to Singapore. For those of you interested, here’s a quick list of tourist attractions I believe are worth visiting, in order of their value for your time:</p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li1">Sentosa Island via cablecar</li>
<li class="li1">Singapore Zoo</li>
<li class="li1">Cloud Forest/Flower Garden &#8211; air conditioned</li>
<li class="li1">SuperTree Grove &#8211; daily shows at 7:45pm and 8:45pm</li>
<li class="li1">Marina Bay Sands</li>
</ol>
<p class="p1">Thanks for reading!</p>
<p class="p1">-AP</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/02/singapore-solocation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embracing Vulnerability &#8211; The Engineer&#8217;s Guide!</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/09/08/embracing-vulnerability-the-engineers-guide/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/09/08/embracing-vulnerability-the-engineers-guide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 04:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brenebrown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifehack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tedtalk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=85</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This past year, I was lucky enough to be introduced to the work of Brene Brown and vulnerability. Brene Brown...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This past year, I was lucky enough to be introduced to the work of Brene Brown and vulnerability. Brene Brown is commonly known as the world&#8217;s foremost vulnerability researcher who covers vulnerability from a research perspective and has spent the past two decades studying courage, vulnerability, shame, and empathy. She has one of the top 5 all-time most viewed <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/brene_brown_on_vulnerability?language=hy">TED Talks</a> about vulnerability which has garnered over 35 million views. Personally, as an engineer and downright textbook left-brained individual, the mushy feeling of vulnerability has always felt incredibly overwhelming. That is, until I came across the work of Brene Brown. Dr. Brown takes an analytical look at vulnerability in her book Daring Greatly, digging into vulnerability with the idea that there are a few repeatable steps you can follow to implement vulnerability in your life, just like a new diet or workout routine. She brilliantly documents her personal struggle with vulnerability when she discovers it is not something that can be incorporated into your life with a formula. Reading her struggles feel eerily similar to the struggles my analytical mind has felt with vulnerability and seeing her mission to accept vulnerability and shame as part of her daily life is an inspiring story to help integrate even the most stoic individual. Having read her book <a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Daring-Greatly-Courage-Vulnerable-Transforms/dp/1592408419?sa-no-redirect=1">Daring Greatly</a> has been one of the most rewarding experiences I have ever been lucky enough to experience. I would truly recommend everyone take the time to read this masterpiece once, and then once more to really let it sink in. But, before digging into it &#8211; here&#8217;s a quick overview of what&#8217;s covered in her TED Talk and the book:</p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Connection is why we are here – it’s what gives purpose and meaning to all our lives</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">SHAME is understood as the fear of disconnection</span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Is there something about me, that if other people know it or see it, that I won’t be worthy of connection?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">No one wants to talk about SHAME – and the less you talk about it, the more you have it</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Shame is basically the “I’m not ______ enough” feeling</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">In order for connection to happen, we have to allow ourselves to be seen, REALLY SEEN(warts and all)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">People who really have a sense of worthiness – a strong sense of love and belonging – and folks who struggle for it ARE ONLY SEPARATED BY ONE VARIABLE </span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">People with a strong sense of love and belong BELIEVE they are WORTHY of a sense of love and belonging…THAT’S IT!!</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">The one thing that keeps most people out of connection is the feeling that we are not worthy of connection</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">There are 4 traits of people who live a wholehearted life</span></li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Courage – tell the story of who you are with a whole heart. Have the courage to be imperfect</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Compassion – be kind to YOURSELF first and then to others</span>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Self-kindness – be warm and understanding towards ourselves when we fail, or feel inadequate, rather than ignoring our pain</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Common humanity – recognize that suffering and feelings of personal inadequacy are part of the shared human experience – we all go through it!</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Mindfulness – take a balanced approach to negative emotions – do not “over identify” with thoughts and feelings so that we are not swept up by negativity.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Talk to yourself the same way you would talk to someone you care about – simple as that! Appreciate the beauty of our cracks and imperfections</span></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Connection – willing to let go of who they thought they should be, in order to be who they were to build strong connection </span>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Good strategy is to carry around a piece of paper in wallet that has names of people whose opinions really matter to you – who love you for your strength and struggles. Aside from these people, you should not care about what any other random humans think of you who have a fleeting impact in your life. </span></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Vulnerability – FULLY embraced vulnerability. They believe that what makes them vulnerable makes them beautiful. The willingness to take the leap of faith and dare greatly.</span></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Humans are very adept at numbing emotions and vulnerability</span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">This generation is the most in-debt, obese, addicted to drugs and alcohol and medicated cohort in adult history</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Problem is – you cannot SELECTIVELY numb emotion. You cannot numb shame, fear, vulnerability selectively. Numbing the bad emotions numbs joy, gratitude, happiness and good feelings as well. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Need to be very cautious about how and why we numb – numb by making the uncertain certain, numb by blaming others, numb by perfection, numb by pretending what we are doing doesn’t have an impact on other people</span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Listen with great care if people love say they are concerned about you engaging in certain type of behaviors</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Main takeaways to practice</span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Let ourselves be seen – really seen </span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Love with our whole heart</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Practice gratitude and joy</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Believe ‘I am enough’ – allows us to be kinder and gentler to ourselves and others around</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Shame-resliency in the workplace. 4 best strategies for building shame resilient organizations are:</span></li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Supporting leaders who are willing to dare greatly and facilitate honest conversations about shame</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Deeply looking into where shame might be functioning in the org </span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Not normalizing shame. Leaders can cultivate engagement by letting people know what to expect – what common struggles are and how other people have dealt with them</span></li>
<li style="font-weight:400;"><span style="font-weight:400;">Training all employees on difference between shame and guilt and how to give and receive feedback in a way that fosters growth and engagement.</span></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/09/08/embracing-vulnerability-the-engineers-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Millennial&#8217;s Guide To Surviving a Long Distance Relationship</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/08/31/the-millennials-guide-to-surviving-a-long-distance-relationship/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/08/31/the-millennials-guide-to-surviving-a-long-distance-relationship/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 04:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bonding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long distance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long distance relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longdistance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longdistancerelationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millenial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=86</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ah, long distance relationships, how I loathe thee. If you have come upon this page, I can only imagine you...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, long distance relationships, how I loathe thee. If you have come upon this page, I can only imagine you are in the middle of a long distance relationship or about to embark on a long distance relationship adventure. Well, fear not &#8211; having survived (albeit with some bumps and bruises) a long distance relationship with a 17 hour time difference and 8998 miles of separation, I have an arsenal of tips to help you out.</p>
<p>First and foremost, before embarking on a long distance relationship &#8211; make sure you are truly committed to the person &#8211; SERIOUSLY &#8211; really make sure you are willing to put up with a lot of nights and days of feeling extremely lonely and frustrated. It is wise to have a conversation about this with your partner and make sure they are on the same page because it takes two wholly committed parties to make this wild adventure work.</p>
<p>Now, there are definitely things you can do to make it suck less, although mind you &#8211; it will SUCK &#8211; A LOT &#8211; LIKE A WHOLE LOT &#8211; at times. Here are a quick 5 tips to help you make it out alive.</p>
<ol>
<li>Get connected on as many apps as possible. Me and my girlfriend had a total of 11 different mediums we were communicating on during our long distance adventure. When the person you want to see most in the world can&#8217;t be physically there with you, it is a really great feeling to get constant updates from them via a plethora of apps and communication platforms. In my personal experience, listening to a song from a Spotify shared playlist that your partner added is the biggest mood booster and can help get you out of a crummy mood quickly.
<ul>
<li>Instagram</li>
<li>Facebook Messenger</li>
<li>Facebook</li>
<li>Snapchat</li>
<li>Spotify Shared Playlist</li>
<li>WhatsApp</li>
<li>Facetime</li>
<li>Texting</li>
<li>Email</li>
<li>Shared Photo Libraries on Icloud</li>
<li>Fitbit Challenges</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Read Books Together!!! &#8211; This should really be tip number 1 but I would recommend taking some time with your partner to talk about common interests and decide a book you are both interested in reading and start your own two person book club. This has a whole lot of benefits for your relationship, starting with a great discussion topic whenever you chat, to imagining your partner reading the book whenever you are reading, to helping you grow mentally rather than numbing your mind away until you see your SigO next. I have read other Long Distance preparation blogs that recommend watching Netflix shows or movies together but I found books were way more valuable for enriching your mind beyond just the few hours of the Netflix binge and the ideas help keep your mind distracted from the long distance annoyance for longer.</li>
<li>Always have your next meet-up planned as early as possible. One of the best and only ways to deal with the mental insanity of long distance is to know that you will have to only deal with it for 32 more days, then 31 more days, then 30 more days. Make sure to have a concrete date set for your meet-ups at all times AND before you leave a meet-up, make sure to plan the next one so you are not completely destroyed on your flight back. Bonus tip: Downloading countdown apps on your phone really helps and a countdown timer to look at every morning is a great reminder that you are getting closer to seeing your boo.</li>
<li>&#8220;Exercise is the most underutilized anti-depressant&#8221; This holds extremely true during long distance. During especially tough times, the endorphin rush from a good workout was the main saving grace to get through another night. My girlfriend and I even participated in a couple of <a href="https://www.shape.com/fitness/workouts/30-day-push-up-challenge">30 day pushup</a> or <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/79938962112500339/">30 day plank </a> challenges &#8211; which aside from being really good for you can help you feel connected with your partner knowing they are doing the same in another city as well. Even a nice walk or jog outside at times is the perfect way to get out of your funk, trust me &#8211; just try it!</li>
<li>Adapt. React. Readapt. Apt. For the non Micheal Scott fans out there, the final tip is to adapt and improve your relationship over time. One of the main things that my lady friend and I did was at the end of every meet-up, we would ask each other what was working well for the other person and what could be improved upon. For example, after feeling disconnected on the day-to-day happenings in each others lives, we decided that an improvement we could make is to send each other snapchats more often &#8211; even if they were of nonsensical happenings throughout the day. Having this conversation on the way to the airport whenever you are super mellow and emotional is also a good idea as it can help you snap out of the emotional anguish and get your rational brain back online to lay out a game plan to improve your relationship.</li>
<li>Bonus Tip: Memes. This post is titled a millennial guide after all. Me and my partner in crime LOVED sharing memes with each other during our LDR. From pictures of goats, to doggos, to Cardi B memes, we had a meme for everything to help brighten each other&#8217;s days. There was even a meme created about the immaturity of handling long distance with memes: <img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-87" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219.jpg" alt="IMG_1219" width="696" height="391" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219.jpg 696w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219-300x169.jpg 300w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219-600x337.jpg 600w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219-590x330.jpg 590w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" /></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hope this helps you brave long distance adventurers out there. Remember, it will all be worth it and you feel like like you have conquered a Herculean task when you are back in the same time zone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/08/31/the-millennials-guide-to-surviving-a-long-distance-relationship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Shit Done for professional procrastinators</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/06/21/getting-shit-done-for-professional-procrastinators/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/06/21/getting-shit-done-for-professional-procrastinators/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 04:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Productivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getshitdone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gettingshitdone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifehack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pomodori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pomodoritechnique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[productivityhack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workmanagement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=80</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever felt the feeling of leaving work with an uneasy feeling in your stomach that you are surely...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever felt the feeling of leaving work with an uneasy feeling in your stomach that you are surely forgetting something on your to-do list but your brain is too fried and distracted to remember it? So have I, very frequently, up till recently when I came across a foolproof way to get all your tasks done at work AND keep your mind organized and sane.</p>
<p>The productivity hack is called The Pomodoro Technique.</p>
<p>If you are not familiar with the technique, the jist of it is as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Work in 25 minute increments</li>
<li>5 minutes of break time after 25 minute work</li>
<li>DO NOT end a pomodori early – if you finish the task with time to spare, review your notes or see if you can enhance the task in any way possible</li>
<li>DO NOT check email during a pomodori – only focused work during this time. How hard is it to work for 25 minutes anyways – a break is coming right after</li>
<li>Mandatory that you take a 5 minute break after each pomodori and a 15 minute break after a set of 4 pomodori &#8211; feel free to check email during this break</li>
<li>If any idea comes up to distract pomodori, simply jot it down and get back to task at hand</li>
<li>Review idea post pomodori completion and add it to To-Do list if still important</li>
<li>If something can be completed under 2 mins, just do it now. Otherwise write it down</li>
<li>If anyone comes by to discuss during Pomodoro, just tell them you’ll get back with them in time after this Pomodoro ends &#8211; no one will get upset by having to wait less than a half hour. This one is really important &#8211; Do not be afraid to say you will get back to them shortly.</li>
</ul>
<p>The way I setup my pomodori list is on a note on my desktop. At the top of the note, I have the rules you see above and below the rules I keep a list of my tasks. Each day starts with looking over these tasks and ensuring the right tasks are on the list for the day and estimating how many 25 minute work increments it will take to complete each task. Each day will be different based on meetings and obligations so I would recommend slicing up the rest of the leftover hours of the day into 25 minute increments and that is how many Pomodori&#8217;s you have to work with. A screenshot of my desktop monitor looks like this: <img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-81" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/image.png" alt="image" width="1600" height="900" /></p>
<p>Anyone can concentrate for 25 minutes at a time, and more often than not, before hitting that 25 minute mark, you will be in a flow state on your current task and can take the 5 minute break to catch up on emails before getting excited for the 25 minute buzzer to sound again so you can get back into the flow.</p>
<p>Since implementing this technique into my daily workday, I have seen my productivity skyrocket and I no longer feel overwhelmed or anxious on a daily basis as was the norm previously. I have also noticed caffeine consumption drop considerably on a daily basis but focus is greatly increased.</p>
<p>Bonus: Chrome has a fantastic plugin for tracking your pomodoro cycles and I highly recommend you use it: https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/marinara-pomodoro%C2%AE-assist/lojgmehidjdhhbmpjfamhpkpodfcodef?utm_source=gmail</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/06/21/getting-shit-done-for-professional-procrastinators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Antigua, Guatemala — The best kept secret in Central America</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 03:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[central america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guatemala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend getaway]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend, I had the pleasure of visiting Guatemala City and Antigua after finding out that flights were completely empty...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="a18a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3">This weekend, I had the pleasure of visiting Guatemala City and Antigua after finding out that flights were completely empty for non-revving down. Upon arriving with Guatemala City with no plans and no research, my first instinct and source of getting tips in the city was to ask the bus driver on the ride over to the hotel. Without skipping a beat, the bus driver recommended heading to Antigua, Guatemala for a day since I was only going to be in Guatemala for less than 48 hours. I made this my priority for the next morning after getting a good night of rest.</p>
<p id="1298" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">After a hearty breakfast and a quick workout, I called an Uber to get over to Antigua from my hotel. Due to bad traffic, the Uber took ~2 hours to get there but I had an amazing ride with the driver who was learning how to speak English and was very candid in sharing his story, albeit in broken English, as well as answer any questions I had about Guatemala. Upon arriving in Antigua, I was blown away by what a beautiful &amp; quaint city it is. First thing I noticed was that the only way to commute around the city is on beautiful cobblestone streets. First stop upon arriving to Antigua was a delicious crepes restaurant named Luna De Meil. I chose this restaurant since it had over 900 reviews and a 4.5 star rating and let me tell you, it did not disappoint! The establishment had a beautiful terrace which complemented the perfect 70 degree weather well and a quick waitstaff to get a delicious chicken and spinach crepe and a banana mango smoothie. I was also able to use the free wifi there to scope out the best itinerary for the day. Post carbo-loading, the next stop was the Iglesias de la Merced- a beautiful church right next to Luna De Meil. After a quick 10 minute stroll through the church, the next stop was a quick 15 minute hike up to Cerro De La Cruz — which had an astounding view of the whole city of Antigua. It was a bit of a tough hike to get up to CDLC and I was a bit winded on a somewhat warm day but it was absolutely worth the amazing view in the end. After soaking in the view by hanging out up top and reading for an hour, I headed back down to visit the next stop on the adventure. According to Trip Advisor, another must do in Antigua was Convento de Las Capuchinas — which are ancient ruins from the 1200s. The ruins were absolutely gorgeous and it was very enlightening to see how nuns lived back in the day when Spain invaded Guatemala. Post embracing the ruins where there was a beautiful wedding taking place, the next stop was walking along the cobblestone streets towards the city’s central park. On the walk over, I couldn’t help but stop into the Museo Chocolate which was a sweet-tooths disneyworld with all kinds of chocolate to sample &amp; chocolate flavored rum — which meant I couldn’t leave without grabbing a couple chocolate bars and a few truffles. Getting back to the regularly scheduled activities led me to the plaza central park — which is a lively park in the middle of Antigua with all kinds of street vendors, live music, and an outdoor market on the weekends. I soaked in the ambiance and rested legs at the park for a quick 5 mintues then headed to Arco de Santa Catalina — which was rated the 2nd best attraction in all of Antigua according to TripAdvisor. The arch was beautiful but really not worthy of the 2nd best rating it was given online — perhaps it would be more enjoyable with a tour guide who could give history about the arch. After all the walking, it was time for grub! I had to consult with my trusty resource — TripAdvisor — and head to the #1 rated restaurant in the city  called &#8216;Porque No?&#8217; Going to school in Austin, I thought I had seen real hole in the wall food joints but this was another level of weird and eccentric. The walls were covered with signatures from everyone who had visited Porque No as well as eccentric art, shoes, and the random-est items your mind could conjure up. I was the first one in line at 6pm when they opened so I was able to get some quality time talking with the waitstaff and bartenders and owner &amp; they were some of the friendliest people I had ever met. They were super welcoming and gave me all the tips of where to go to really enjoy Antigua and even informed me a celebrity wedding had taken place just the weekend before in Antigua. I ordered a few Sangria’s(red and white) since I don’t discriminate with Sangria colors and then a grilled eggplant based on the bartenders recommendation. The drinks and the food were incredible and the whole meal cost under $20, what a treat! I was also able to pick the waitstaff’s brain for a great bar to check out on Saturday night and they recommended me to No Se — a Mezcal bar walking distance from Porque No which just happened to be rated the #1 bar in the city. Post having a happy belly, I headed to No Se and was blown away by what a cool and dank bar it was. The whole bar was only illuminated by candles and there was 3 separate rooms within the bar which all had a set of bartenders. It was a blast to hang out at the bar because again, the bartenders were super friendly and I was able to chat with a bartender from Italy who had moved to Guatemala after spending a couple of years in Australia before. A travel nomad that had me green with envy. While hanging at the bar, I also struck up with a friendly traveler next to me who was a real GOT (Goat of Traveling) who told me he is spending 6 months on each continent traveling around to really soak up the culture. Currently, he’s hanging out in Guatemala for 3 months for a volunteering opportunity for teaching English to super low income kids and was heading to explore the rest of Central America afterwards. It was super refreshing to meet someone who was so C’iest La Vie about really soaking up all opportunities that traveling have to offer and left me super inspired. I had a few Mezcal drinks at No Se while enjoying some great conversation before heading out since I had a 7am flight back to Dallas the next morning. I grabbed an Uber which luckily only took 40 minutes to get back and had a great time reminiscing on the incredible day of exploring Guatemala.</p>

<a href='https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/guatemala1/'><img width="150" height="150" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-92x92.jpeg 92w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-140x140.jpeg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>
<a href='https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/guatemala2/'><img width="150" height="150" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-92x92.jpeg 92w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-140x140.jpeg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>

]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The quintessential list of all the best travel advice from an Airline Employee</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/16/the-quintessential-list-of-all-the-best-travel-advice-from-an-airline-employee/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/16/the-quintessential-list-of-all-the-best-travel-advice-from-an-airline-employee/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 04:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheapflights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheapvacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travelhacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=62</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wanna travel for cheap? Here's all the tips for how to do it!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a post of my collection of all the extremely valuable resources and articles I have hoard&#8230;err&#8230;collected over time of working for an airline. Enjoy!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.frommers.com/blogs/arthur-frommer-online/blog_posts/it-matters-what-day-of-the-week-you-book-airfares-a-new-study" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cheapest Day to Book Airline Tickets</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bestproducts.com/fun-things-to-do/a1163/best-time-day-to-buy-airline-tickets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Best Time of Day to Buy Airline Tickets </a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.travelandleisure.com/trip-ideas/budget-travel/cheap-hotel-room-trick" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How to Book the Cheapest Hotels</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/best-travel-apps-in-2017-2017-8/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Best Apps to Make Travel Easier</a></li>
<li><a href="http://time.com/money/4895917/best-discount-luxury-hotel-booking-sites/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11 Websites to book Luxury Hotels for Cheap</a></li>
<li>Must have Flight Comparison Tools
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/flights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Flights</a></li>
<li><a href="https://skiplagged.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Skiplagged</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.momondo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Momondo</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.cntraveler.com/story/google-flights-hacks-that-save-you-time-and-money" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Flight Usage Hacks</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40430882/this-airplane-gadget-makes-flying-long-distances-in-coach-almost-bearable?partner=rss&amp;utm_campaign=rss+fastcompany&amp;utm_content=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=rss" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Airplane Gadget to Make Long Distance Flights in Coach Bearable</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/travelisfree/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook page that reports error fares</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurabegleybloom/2017/04/13/37-ways-to-game-the-airlines-how-to-get-free-flights-travel-upgrades-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">37 ways to game the airlines</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.travelchannel.com/roam-blog/news-deals/great-tips-on-booking-cheap-flights" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8 Great Tips for booking cheap flights</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.popsci.com/how-to-book-cheapest-flights#page-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Use Tech and Tools to book cheapest flights possible</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/16/the-quintessential-list-of-all-the-best-travel-advice-from-an-airline-employee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Day Journey to Improve Performance of your AngularJS application</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/13/5-day-journey-to-improve-performance-of-your-angularjs-application/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/13/5-day-journey-to-improve-performance-of-your-angularjs-application/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=49</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently I came across a project where I had to take on the job of reducing the total watcher count...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="graf graf--p">Recently I came across a project where I had to take on the job of reducing the total watcher count on a website where the total data set visible to the user was potentially infinite. As a bonus, this website had to be responsive and usable on any and all devices of all shapes and sizes — this post documents my 5 day journey to reduce the watcher count of an AngularJS 1.4 application to a managable state. Hopefully you are not in the same predicatment as me and are using Angular or React by this point &#8211; c&#8217;mon it&#8217;s 2018 &#8211; what are you waiting for?! But if you are not, I sympathize with you and encourage you to read on.</p>
<p class="graf graf--p"><strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong">Day 1:</strong></p>
<p class="graf graf--p">First and foremost, before embarking on the journey to reduce the overall watcher count — I had to arm myself with the right tools. After a bit of frantic googling — I came across the following two plugins that would help me get a grasp on how bloated the applications UI was with watchers and help to pinpoint which elements were the biggest offenders. I’d highly recommend installing these two Chrome plugins:</p>
<ol class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Angular Total Watchers —  <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/angular-watchers/nlmjblobloedpmkmmckeehnbfalnjnjk?hl=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Total Watcher Count Plugin</a></li>
<li class="graf graf--li">AngularJs Batarang- <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/angularjs-batarang/ighdmehidhipcmcojjgiloacoafjmpfk?hl=en-US" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Detailed Watcher Breakdown Plugin</a></li>
</ol>
<p class="graf graf--p"><strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong">Day 2:</strong></p>
<p class="graf graf--p">Armed with the toolset to get control of the watcher count, the next assignment was to blindly open as many tabs as possible for anything related to AngularJs watcher count reduction and start to compile knowledge. All a half day of research, I can safely say that I have compiled the best articles to help you understand Angular Watchers in the simplest terms possible.</p>
<ol class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Perhaps the most valuable use of time to help you get your watcher count down will be to first understand how the Ins and Outs of AngularJS really work — especially the digest cycle — which is where all the watchers are evaluated. The brilliant Minko Gevchev has setup a skinny version of AngularJS on his github respository and written an invaluable post on understanding  <a href="http://blog.mgechev.com/2015/03/09/build-learn-your-own-light-lightweight-angularjs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bare bones of AngularJs</a> . I would highly recommend checking out his GitHub repo for the lightweight AngularJS as well and set breakpoints to debug through the digest cycle to understand what happens <a href="https://github.com/mgechev/light-angularjs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">under the hood of AngularJS</a>. This will not only help you with reducing the watcher count on your page but also set you up for writing high performance code in your future AngularJS projects.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Here are a few more valuable resources on <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="http://techiejs.com/Blog/Post/Understanding-The-AngularJS-Digest-Loop" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">understanding Dirty Checking</a> and the <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://www.ng-book.com/p/The-Digest-Loop-and-apply/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">digest cycle of AngularJS</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p class="graf graf--p">I understand that we are on day 2 of the Journey already and no code has been modified to reduce the watcher count but I would highly recommend not skipping ahead and understanding why a higher watcher count slows down an AngularJs application before getting your hands dirty with coding.</p>
<p class="graf graf--p"><strong class="markup--strong markup--p-strong">Day 3:</strong></p>
<p class="graf graf--p">One-Time binding to the rescue! Perhaps the most valuable resource you will come across for reducing total AngularJS watchers is one-time binding. The basic theory behind one time binding is that for elements on your page that only need to be rendered once and will not be changed based on user interaction should use one-time binding. I would recommend using the following steps for applying one-time binding:</p>
<ol>
<li>Take stock of what your total watcher count is using the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/angular-watchers/nlmjblobloedpmkmmckeehnbfalnjnjk?hl=en-US">Angular Total Watchers Plugin</a> recommended above &#8211; you did download the plugin right?</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t be discouraged if the watcher count is incredibly high. We will reduce it to a manageable number before the end of this article</li>
<li>Open up your html code and do a global find for the text &#8220;{{&#8221; and replace it with &#8220;{{::&#8221;. Refresh your page and observe total watcher count drop dramatically for your page like magic.</li>
<li>Repeat step 3 but do a global search for &#8216; ng-if=&#8221; &#8216; and replace with &#8216; ng-if=&#8221;:: &#8216;. Also follow this syntax for ng-show, ng-disabled, and basically any other ng-* directives.</li>
<li>Your watcher count should be incredibly low at this point and your app&#8217;s look and feel should be exactly the same upon page load. But, unfortunately &#8211; all user interaction on the page will not function anymore.</li>
<li>Go through all the places in your html code where you applied one time binding and determine whether the values of these directives will change based on user interaction with the page. If they only need to be displayed once to the user and will never change until page refresh, leave the one-time binding and move on. For the data elements that could change based on user interaction or new data &#8211; remove the one-time binding syntax :: off the html elements.</li>
<li>Refresh your page after you have gone through this exercise and observe that your watcher count should be in a lot more managable state now.</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>NOTE: </strong></span> One-time binding was only added to the AngularJS core in version 1.3. If you are using an earlier version than 1.3, please navigate over to the <a href="https://github.com/Pasvaz/bindonce">Bind-Once</a> plugin and implement in your code which will give you the same functionality as the 1.3 and beyond :: syntax.</p>
<p><strong>Day 4</strong>:</p>
<p>The next code optimization will discuss improving performance on the ng-repeat directives in your application. Look &#8211; if you have used AngularJS &#8211; you gotta love ng-repeat. It&#8217;s simple implementation and vast power is one of the best features of AngularJS. But, it certainly comes with it&#8217;s drawbacks when the total elements in the array it is being applied to starts to grow. Consider the code block below:</p>
<p>&lt;ul ng-repeat=&#8221;beer in beers&#8221;&gt; &lt;li&gt;{{beer.name}}&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</p>
<p>If you have applied one-time binding to your element within the ng-repeat {{::beer}} and don&#8217;t have to worry about the elements in beers array changing, you are in great shape already. BUT, if you have a dynamic list of beers based on user interaction or filtering, you will notice your page will re-render extremely slowly based on user interaction. Assuming that you have a dynamic list that can be filtered or refreshed based on new data being retrieved from the server, you are likely to have code along the lines of $scope.beers = newBeersFromServer based on a user click. Even if the list of beers retrieved from the server has ONLY one more beer in the array, angular logic will go through and erase all the DOM elements on your UI and repaint them &#8211; an extremely expensive operation. How to improve this you ask? By using another awesome feature you have likely heard of called trackBy. (Note: trackBy was added to Angular core in 1.1.4 so the implementation below will not work for you if you are using an older version of AngularJS). A high level explanation for trackBy goes as follows: AngularJS appends a unique $$hashKey property to every element in your array so that ng-repeat can ensure that it is not rendering any element twice. Every-time your list is refreshed, ng-repeat will &#8211; unfortunately &#8211; go through your whole list and assign a new $$hashKey to every element in the list and repaint the entire DOM again. Instead of using the native $$hashKey to allow ng-repeat to keep track of your elements, AngularJS allows you to specify a unique property in each element in your array for AngularJS to use for rendering and tracking for changes and updates. Using this knowledge, we can update the code above to state:</p>
<p>&lt;ul ng-repeat=&#8221;beer in beers track by beer.id&#8221;&gt; &lt;li&gt;{{beer.name}}&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</p>
<p>Here, we are assuming every beer in your list has a different ID and that ID for each beer stays the same in your database throughout it&#8217;s life. Now, whenever Angular re-renders your UI, it does need to dynamically repaint the DOM for every single beer in your list as it sees that prior to refresh and after refresh, the ID for most of the beers in your list are the same. AngularJs knows to only add the DOM elements for new beers which it was previously not tracking in the beers list &#8211; aka the new beers that were fetched from the server. Check out <a href="http://jsfiddle.net/SeKk7/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this fiddle</a> to get a better understanding of the power of trackBy. By default, the code is not using trackBy to render the list of elements and is painfully slow. Once you enable trackBy &#8211; the refresh will be lightning fast as Angular will have no need to repaint the DOM. It really is THAT SIMPLE to improve a noticeable improvement in the re-rendering of your list inside the ng-repeat. Simple rule to follow: If you are using ng-repeat, you should use trackBy.</p>
<p><strong>Day 5:</strong></p>
<p>Today, we will discuss ng-if and the power it has to improve your application rendering dramatically. First, a quick primer on ng-if versus ng-show. Using ng-if is (almost always) recommended over ng-show. The reason is as follows: ng-if actually dynamically adds and removes DOM elements from your DOM whereas ng-show will just change the visibility from display: none to display: block. You can already imagine how using ng-if will greatly reduce the total number of watchers in your application, especially if you have multiple ng-ifs inside a ng-repeat. ng-if is easy enough to understand, but please follow the <a href="https://docs.angularjs.org/api/ng/directive/ngIf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AngularJS core docs</a> to get a better understanding of the directive. To watch the watcher count in your application drop considerably if you have a lot of ng-show directives, do a find all on &#8220;ng-show&#8221; and replace with &#8220;ng-if&#8221; and notice the total watcher count of your application drop using the watcher count plugin. Although implementing ng-if will already considerably improve your performance, another enhanced implementation of ng-if is using ng-if-start and ng-if-end(2 directives that were added to AngularJs as of version 1.2). Consider the code example below:</p>
<div>
<p> {{beer.name}}</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>{{beer.strength}}</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>{{beer.countryOfOrigin}}</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>{{beer.totalHops}}</p>
</div>
<ul>
<li>Instead of having to use multiple ng-ifs in your code, you could change the structure of your code to the following:</li>
</ul>
<div>
<p> {{beer.name}}</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>{{beer.totalHops}}</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>{{beer.countryOfOrigin}}</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>{{beer.strength}}</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Above, you can notice &#8211; that you have the same ng-if statement applied to multiple elements in your DOM &#8211; angular will add a watcher to every single ng-if element. This would lead to the application having 3 watchers in the first code example above for each ng-if=&#8221;beer.ipa&#8221;. BUT, since you have multiple ng-ifs with the same check, you can restructure your code to use ng-if-start and ng-if-end to reduce your watcher count to 2, 1 for each of the ng-if-start and ng-if-end. While this doesn&#8217;t seem like a noticeable difference of watcher count reduction, any watcher count reduction within a ng-repeat can prove to be extremely valuable as the list of elements in your ng-repeat grows.</p>
<p><strong>Summing Up:</strong></p>
<p>Alas, we have come to the end of our journey and 5 day work week of improving the performance of our AngularJS application. The final step of the journey is to once again open up the AngularJS watcher count plugin and go through each of the pages on your application to observe total watcher count. As recommended by the AngularJS core team, each page in your application should have under 2000 watchers. Once we get above 2000 watchers, you will notice a considerable performance drop in your UI and your page will start crawling, especially on old phones and laptops. If your watcher count is already under 2k for each of the pages in your application, you are likely in good shape and can be confident in knowing your application is well optimized- but if you wish to optimize your application further I would recommend the resources below for improving your application performance even further. As you can see, a few simple changes can make a huge difference in performance when it comes to AngularJS. I hope the above tips help you in developing a responsive and speedy application.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.alexkras.com/11-tips-to-improve-angularjs-performance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11 tips to Improve AngularJS performance</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.binpress.com/tutorial/speeding-up-angular-js-with-simple-optimizations/135" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Speed up AngularJS Performance with simple optimizations</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/13/5-day-journey-to-improve-performance-of-your-angularjs-application/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The &#8216;this&#8217; keyword in Javascript</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2017/11/12/the-this-keyword-in-javascript/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2017/11/12/the-this-keyword-in-javascript/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 06:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This keyword in javascript explained based on the javascript launchpad lecture course from Simple Programmer. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before reading this post, just remember that the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword is a very confusing topic to understand in javascript and many believe that the way it is programmed in javascript is actually wrong and contains a bug. Do not get discouraged and confused when reading this lecture &#8211; and if you do just come back and re-read it a few more times till it starts to make sense. Also, having a browser with Chrome Developer Tools open really helps solidify the concepts in this lesson about this. Anyways, on to the lesson.</p>
<p>Two quick links that are very important to mention:</p>
<ol>
<li>Incredible detailed video about this lesson can be found at: https://drive.google.com/file/d/11mu-BBkou7BV__Sf5chJaj2rAwHW8AzL/view?usp=sharing</li>
<li>The method used to explain the concepts in this post is based on the Feynman technique &#8211; the best way to learn anything fast: https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2012/04/learn-anything-faster-with-the-feynman-technique/</li>
</ol>
<p>Step 1: Write out what I know about the subject using simple language and common jargon:</p>
<p>Before we start talking about the keyword &#8216;this&#8217;, we need to understand how the javascript engine interprets Javascript code. Whenever code is run in javascript, it&#8217;s run inside an execution context &#8211;  which is basically a wrapper that wraps up the currently executing code. Whenever JS engine first starts to interpret code, it creates a global execution context with a global object, a special variable called &#8216;this&#8217;, and a link to the outer environment(more to come on that later). On the global execution context, the &#8216;this&#8217; variable is set to Window object because we are running javascript in the browser. The global object is set to Window too whenever we are running javascript in a browser.  Now whenever any code is written in our JS file, it is attached to the global object. Example: If our JS file just has one line of code that says  var a = &#8220;Hello&#8221;, the variable a will be a property on the global window object and you can go into chrome developer tools and type window.a and see that the value &#8220;hello&#8221; is output. Whenever the JS engine is creating the execution context to interpret our code, it does so in two phases. The Creation Phase and the Execution Phase. In the first phase of code rendering, the JS engine sets up the global object, &#8216;this&#8217; and makes sure they have places in memory. Also in this phase, the javascript parser runs through your code and sets up memory space for variables and functions. This step of actually setting up memory space for variables and functions is called &#8216;hoisting&#8217;. In phase one, your code is not actually executed but memory space is assigned for your variables and functions so that they exist in memory. Functions and variables behave a bit differently when they are given memory space. Functions are completely put into memory, including the code inside the function. Variables are just given a memory space and set to undefined &#8211; which is a value that acts as a placeholder until the execution phase of creating the execution context occurs. In phase 2, your code is actually executed using the things setup in the creation phase like the global object, &#8216;this&#8217;, and outer environment reference. The code you have written is run line by line, converting it, compiling it, and finally presenting it as something the computer can understand. Since there is already space in memory for your variables and functions, the code is run line by line in this phase and if it comes across a variable, either the code will use &#8216;undefined&#8217; for the variable if it has not been actually set in our code, or it will use the value the variable is set to. All of this is just a big primer to understand the execution context and how it is created in two phases so that you can get a better understanding of the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword coming up.</p>
<p>Whenever a function is run in your code during the execution phase of the execution context setup, a new execution context is created for every function. This execution context created for the function brings with it the usual characteristics of an execution context &#8211; a variable environment where all the variables created inside that function live, a reference to an outer lexical environment so the execution context knows where to look down the scope chain if it can&#8217;t find a variable in it&#8217;s current execution context, AND of course the keyword &#8216;this&#8217;. &#8216;this&#8217; keyword can point to different things depending on HOW the function that a new execution context is created for is invoked. Whenever you create a function in your by typing either function &#8216;anyName'() or by doing var a = function() -&gt; the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword will point to the global window object inside either of those functions execution contexts. Now, if you create a method inside an object literal instead of just a property, the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword will be set differently. For reference, whenever a primitive value is assigned to an object, it is called an object property. But whenever a function is assigned to an object, it is called an object method. For example, var c = { name: &#8216;the C object&#8217;, log: function(){ console.log(this) }; } Whenever a user calls c.log() in the code, the following steps occur. A new execution context is created for the anonymous function log whenever c.log() is invoked. The &#8216;this&#8217; property for this execution context is set to the variable c instead of the outer window global object. Only when a function is a method within an object is the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword set to the object the function method is sitting inside of. Again, the this keyword is just pointing to a reference of the object and doesn&#8217;t actually make a new copy of the object. As a method of the object that contains you, a method of an object can mutate the surrounding object using the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword. Only and ONLY whenever a function is a method on an object is the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword set to the the object that the method sits in. Otherwise, &#8216;this&#8217; will always point to the global window object. EVEN IF a method on an object has another function created inside it, the execution context created for the function inside the method will have the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword set to the global window object. A lot of people consider this a bug in javascript and that is why a lot of code will have var self = this; as the first line of code to ensure that if you are writing functions within an object method that are relying on properties from the object in the functions, they will point to the object reference that is stored in the &#8216;self&#8217; variable rather than the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword that changes constantly every-time a new execution context is setup. There is only 2 values &#8216;this&#8217; can hold:</p>
<ol>
<li>Reference to the global object &#8211; happens whenever a function is created as a normal function expression or a function is assigned to a variable. In this scenario, whenever the execution context is created for the function when it is run, &#8216;this&#8217; points to just the global object</li>
<li>Reference to the object in which the method was created &#8211; if we create a method in an object (a function within object) &#8211; the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword points to the object that holds that method. BUT, if we create another function within this method and invoke that function, whenever the execution context for the function inside the method is created, the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword points to the global variable window again. Which is why we must use self=this in the beginning of a method rather than rely on the &#8216;this&#8217; keyword in our method declaration to always point to the object where the method is defined.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This post was first created on 11/11/17 &#8211; it is still too wordy and needs to be cleaned up and made easier to understand soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2017/11/12/the-this-keyword-in-javascript/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Labor Day in Montana</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2012/09/04/labor-day-in-montana/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2012/09/04/labor-day-in-montana/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 22:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andypande.wordpress.com/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Phew&#8230;writing this on Tuesday afternoon when returning to work after long and exciting 3 day weekend in Montana. Best highlights...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Phew&#8230;writing this on Tuesday afternoon when returning to work after long and exciting 3 day weekend in Montana. Best highlights of the trip for those who don&#8217;t wan&#8217;t to read the novel I&#8217;m about to write goes like this: Billings downtown is crazy, people are amazing and extremely friendly, Yellowstone is absolutely gorgeous with tons of Bison, Thest Bison are extremely&#8230;bold &amp; friendly and walk through middle of roads and even participate in mating season in front of park guests, &amp; finally Boat tours and Whitewater rafting in Yellowstone is incredible.</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;m going to try to break down the trip day by day in detail:</p>
<p>Friday(August 31st, 2012):</p>
<p>Left work around 3:30 to catch the 5:00 pm flight to Denver. As soon as landing in Denver, met up with Shivan in the United Club East. First experience in Airline club turned out to be exciting and downed 3 White Russians and a Blue Moon in about an hour. From there, got on flight from Denver to Billings, landing in Billings about 30 mins late around 10 pm. Got a rental car in Billings and went straight to Shivan&#8217;s hotel &#8211; Hilton garden Inn to put away bags and get ready to go out in Downtown Billings. Went to couple of brewery/bar deals in downtown which had cheap $2 beers and Casinos inside the bars. Me and Shivan chilled for a bit &amp; downed a brew or three while Shivan gave a tour of the cool bars around. Around 11:30, left to pick up Aneesh from the airport and came straight back to the bars downtown. Moved around to a couple bars until we settled on one bar that Shivan recommended. Met a local at the bar who was really chill and bought all 3 of us shots while giving us advice for what to do in Yellowstone and how to avoid bears. Soon after, went outside in this bar to find a group of young kids dressed in Jabbawockeez masks with a boombox set up on the street dancing and asking for tips. Saw these random kids dance with some of the bar patrons joining in for about 30 mins until Aneesh almost got in a fight and then bounced to the next bar. Next, checked out a placed called Rainbow Bar(no homo) that actually sold mini liquor bottles behind the bar&#8230;genius idea. After Rainbow bar, we were pretty drunk so headed back to the hotel to pass out. Passed out pretty soon after getting back while watching Harold and Kumar Christmas and got ready for &#8216;rents to arrive next morning around 10 and head over to Yellowstone.</p>
<p>Saturday(September 1st, 2012):</p>
<p>Woke up around 10:30 when rents arrived to the Hotel. Went down and had an amazing breakfast in the Hilton while chatting with the rents then headed out to grab groceries and head to Yellowstone. Took a super scenic route to Yellowstone through Bear Tooth Pass where we went up 10,000 feet in elevation and had an amazing lookout. (Insert Pic here) Kumud Mami was literally shitting her pants at this point because she is super afraid of heights and driving on a narrow road without railings did not help the cause. After the awesome drive and stopping every 10 mins for pictures, we ended up pulling up to a lookout lower on the peak that had a river you could wade into. Naturally, started throwing around the pigskin by the river and as soon as the games started, the football was in the water minutes later. Me and Ketan had to set up a rescue mission the river where we cornered the ball from both sides before it floated off into the rapids and was lost forever. Lucklly, we were able to retrieve the ball and minor hiccup aside, we continued on towards Yellowstone to check out some more scenic lookouts. After getting into the park, we stopped at a couple of spots to take some pictures, the coolest of which being an awesome waterfall which we had to hike down (&amp; up) 2 miles to get to see. INSERT FALLS PIC here. As soon as we came up from the falls, it started to pour rain and sleet so we all piled into the cars and headed for the Lake Lodge to check in. Upon arriving at the lodge, checked in right away and ran to the rooms to make some sandwiches since we had not eaten all day since breakfast. Chowed down on some sammies in the room and drank a couple brews then the bacchas headed for the lobby to grab some more drinks and check out the bar. By this time, we were all completely wiped out and the drink  prices were not exactly cheap, so me Aneesh and Ketan got a drink each and then headed back to the room right after. We were able to find out that BYOB was acceptable in the lobby so we were set on getting a bottle of liquor and lots of brews to the lobby when we returned the next night.</p>
<p>Sunday(9/2/12):</p>
<p>Woke up around 10 and headed to the Cafeteria in the lobby to grab some breakfast. Had a big hearty breakfast and set out for a day of adventuring the park. First stop was a quick 1 mile hike which went by a beach and lots of forest. Stopped at the beach to have a full photoshoot with jumping pics etc. and tossed around the pigskin. INSERT BEACH PICTURE HERE. From there, walked around and lazily finished the hike while taking waaay too many pictures along the way. Got back to the car and decided we were going to go check out Old Faithful &#8211; aka biggest and oldest geyser in the whole park. Otw to Old Faithful, stopped off at some smaller mud flats and geysers we saw along the way that lay on top of &#8216;Thin Crust&#8217; &#8211; which just made everyone hungrier since we had taken a long hike. After quick stop for geyser, we made another stop for Sandwiches lunch at a Picnic spot with next stop being Old Faith himself. Got to O.F. just in time for Geyser explosion and sat and watched the geyser bubble and shoot white hot steam and water all over everyone for a quick 5-10 mins. After this, had some time to kill so checked out Old Faithful Inn and hung out in there while grabbing some coffee and just exploring the gift shops and inn that were built in the 1800s. After chilling there for a bit, decided to head out to another awesome BlackSmith geyser that was on a list of &#8216;Top 10 things to Do in Yellowstone.&#8217; This geyser was awesome because it allowed you to get right up to the steam and be able to put your hand (illegally) in the hot water while getting real close. After getting burnt out on geysers, we decided to head to a different lookout point for the falls from Saturday so Shivan could get his picture perfect moment. Over there, grabbed a lot more pics of the falls, with a couple of hilarious anomaly pictures mixed in. Oversaturated with nature and pictures in general, we then decided to head to back to the hotel and get changed real quick so we could come back and grab dinner in the cafeteria before it closer. Got some delicious grub in the Caf before heading out to the lobby with beer and liquor bottles we had found earlier equipped in hand, ready to do it BIG that night. Hung out with rents and played cards for an hour or two while they got buzzed and were ready to pass out, then the real fun started. As soon as the rents bounced, started taking swigs straight out of the Yellowstone Bourbon bottle we had found earlier and moved onto more fun card games like Fuck the Dealer. Got somewhat inebriated after a couple games of FTD so we decided to head out to the porch to smoke a few cigars(also picked up earlier at Old Faithful Inn). When I said, this is when the fun started earlier&#8230;the fun actually did not start till this point. Within minutes of hanging outside and smoking cigars, we were approached by Bison which apparently had no problems roaming around the lodge chock full of people. The bison got literally within 10 feet of us, and we even saw a Bison get on it&#8217;s hind legs and go full out Sandusky onto another Bison(as mentioned in the summary). As if this wasn&#8217;t crazy enough, while smoking the cigars we saw some lights flashing across Yellowstone lake where we knew there was no inhabitable, which we later found out was an SOS call that we completely ignored. Following this ridiculous run of events, we didn&#8217;t know what to do but to go pound more bourbon and knock out our initial goal of finishing the bottle before the end of the night. This did not take long and we were soon done with the bourbon and moving onto beers from the cooler. We stayed at the lodge till about 1:30 when we were kicked out by the Security guard who had to close up shop, but we weren&#8217;t done drinking yet so we headed back to the porch to continue the shenanigans. It was at this point that we found out that the lights across the lake was an SOS since we saw police lights flashing in the same point where we had seen the SOS literally 20 minutes later. This led to the night being sworn in secrecy and not shared with anyone. The night eventually ended with us hanging out on the porch shooting the shit and having general drunk convos until we got too cold and decided to go pass out. Got to our cabins and passed out right away, completing our goal of knocking out the bottle of bourbon with no problems.</p>
<p>Note: Omitted from Saturday &#8211;</p>
<ul>
<li>Boat tour in the morning before the hike</li>
<li>Bison stampede before heading back to the lodge for dinner</li>
</ul>
<p>Monday (9/3/12):</p>
<p>Woke up lazily after getting pretty hammered the night before,  but suprisingly not hungover at all. Went to the lodge in the morning because Shivan had lost his camera(surpise surprise) and to check out. Camera found, headed out to lookout point next to the hotel to have some PB&amp;J breakfast sandwiches and check out the lodge hotel. Post hotel, went out to a trail we wanted to hike before heading out of Yellowstone. Trail was about 4 miles long and pretty amazing with lots of beautiful scenery, lakes and amazing lookouts over the canyon and waterfall(INSERT LOOKOUT PICTURE HERE). The hike finally ended at a stop called artist point where there was an amazing lookout of the famous waterfall where we hung out for a bit and took some more anomaly pics&#8230;Actually, took the best anomaly pic of them all (INSERT ANOMALY PIC HERE) before heading out on the road to get out to our whitewater rafting appointment. Before the whitewater tour, stopped real quick to grab some ice-cream and water refills, then headed out of yellowstone. Got to Montana Whitewater and quickly changed into swimming gear got a quick briefing before heading out onto the river and rapids. Rapids were pretty fun and whitewater tour overall was pretty awesome with a lot of level 3 &amp; 4 rapids but nothing as intense or lifethreatening as rapids in Alaska. After 3 hour whitewater tour, got recommendations from tour guide about best restaurants around Whitewater shop and got recommendation for a cool place called LightHouse cafe. Food at lighthouse cafe was incredible with some great Steak, Lamb, and Buffalo burgers and was well deserved as first full meal that wasn&#8217;t sandwiches. After great feast that included amazing dessert as well, started the 3 hour drive back to Billings, with Aneesh driving the whole way. Drive was fun because we hooked up Donald Glover standup to AUX and set up tablet on dashboard of car so we had hater vision while driving. Post drive, the Dattas checked into their hotel and Pandes headed back to our hotel from Friday night and passed out soon after checking out some pictures. Woke up next morning to take early 6 am flight back to Dallas via Denver and that was the end of an amazing Montana weekend!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2012/09/04/labor-day-in-montana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
