<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>guatemala &#8211; Andy Pande</title>
	<atom:link href="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/tag/guatemala/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/</link>
	<description>Web Development Enthusiast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 03:11:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Antigua, Guatemala — The best kept secret in Central America</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 03:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[central america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guatemala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend getaway]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend, I had the pleasure of visiting Guatemala City and Antigua after finding out that flights were completely empty...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="a18a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3">This weekend, I had the pleasure of visiting Guatemala City and Antigua after finding out that flights were completely empty for non-revving down. Upon arriving with Guatemala City with no plans and no research, my first instinct and source of getting tips in the city was to ask the bus driver on the ride over to the hotel. Without skipping a beat, the bus driver recommended heading to Antigua, Guatemala for a day since I was only going to be in Guatemala for less than 48 hours. I made this my priority for the next morning after getting a good night of rest.</p>
<p id="1298" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">After a hearty breakfast and a quick workout, I called an Uber to get over to Antigua from my hotel. Due to bad traffic, the Uber took ~2 hours to get there but I had an amazing ride with the driver who was learning how to speak English and was very candid in sharing his story, albeit in broken English, as well as answer any questions I had about Guatemala. Upon arriving in Antigua, I was blown away by what a beautiful &amp; quaint city it is. First thing I noticed was that the only way to commute around the city is on beautiful cobblestone streets. First stop upon arriving to Antigua was a delicious crepes restaurant named Luna De Meil. I chose this restaurant since it had over 900 reviews and a 4.5 star rating and let me tell you, it did not disappoint! The establishment had a beautiful terrace which complemented the perfect 70 degree weather well and a quick waitstaff to get a delicious chicken and spinach crepe and a banana mango smoothie. I was also able to use the free wifi there to scope out the best itinerary for the day. Post carbo-loading, the next stop was the Iglesias de la Merced- a beautiful church right next to Luna De Meil. After a quick 10 minute stroll through the church, the next stop was a quick 15 minute hike up to Cerro De La Cruz — which had an astounding view of the whole city of Antigua. It was a bit of a tough hike to get up to CDLC and I was a bit winded on a somewhat warm day but it was absolutely worth the amazing view in the end. After soaking in the view by hanging out up top and reading for an hour, I headed back down to visit the next stop on the adventure. According to Trip Advisor, another must do in Antigua was Convento de Las Capuchinas — which are ancient ruins from the 1200s. The ruins were absolutely gorgeous and it was very enlightening to see how nuns lived back in the day when Spain invaded Guatemala. Post embracing the ruins where there was a beautiful wedding taking place, the next stop was walking along the cobblestone streets towards the city’s central park. On the walk over, I couldn’t help but stop into the Museo Chocolate which was a sweet-tooths disneyworld with all kinds of chocolate to sample &amp; chocolate flavored rum — which meant I couldn’t leave without grabbing a couple chocolate bars and a few truffles. Getting back to the regularly scheduled activities led me to the plaza central park — which is a lively park in the middle of Antigua with all kinds of street vendors, live music, and an outdoor market on the weekends. I soaked in the ambiance and rested legs at the park for a quick 5 mintues then headed to Arco de Santa Catalina — which was rated the 2nd best attraction in all of Antigua according to TripAdvisor. The arch was beautiful but really not worthy of the 2nd best rating it was given online — perhaps it would be more enjoyable with a tour guide who could give history about the arch. After all the walking, it was time for grub! I had to consult with my trusty resource — TripAdvisor — and head to the #1 rated restaurant in the city  called &#8216;Porque No?&#8217; Going to school in Austin, I thought I had seen real hole in the wall food joints but this was another level of weird and eccentric. The walls were covered with signatures from everyone who had visited Porque No as well as eccentric art, shoes, and the random-est items your mind could conjure up. I was the first one in line at 6pm when they opened so I was able to get some quality time talking with the waitstaff and bartenders and owner &amp; they were some of the friendliest people I had ever met. They were super welcoming and gave me all the tips of where to go to really enjoy Antigua and even informed me a celebrity wedding had taken place just the weekend before in Antigua. I ordered a few Sangria’s(red and white) since I don’t discriminate with Sangria colors and then a grilled eggplant based on the bartenders recommendation. The drinks and the food were incredible and the whole meal cost under $20, what a treat! I was also able to pick the waitstaff’s brain for a great bar to check out on Saturday night and they recommended me to No Se — a Mezcal bar walking distance from Porque No which just happened to be rated the #1 bar in the city. Post having a happy belly, I headed to No Se and was blown away by what a cool and dank bar it was. The whole bar was only illuminated by candles and there was 3 separate rooms within the bar which all had a set of bartenders. It was a blast to hang out at the bar because again, the bartenders were super friendly and I was able to chat with a bartender from Italy who had moved to Guatemala after spending a couple of years in Australia before. A travel nomad that had me green with envy. While hanging at the bar, I also struck up with a friendly traveler next to me who was a real GOT (Goat of Traveling) who told me he is spending 6 months on each continent traveling around to really soak up the culture. Currently, he’s hanging out in Guatemala for 3 months for a volunteering opportunity for teaching English to super low income kids and was heading to explore the rest of Central America afterwards. It was super refreshing to meet someone who was so C’iest La Vie about really soaking up all opportunities that traveling have to offer and left me super inspired. I had a few Mezcal drinks at No Se while enjoying some great conversation before heading out since I had a 7am flight back to Dallas the next morning. I grabbed an Uber which luckily only took 40 minutes to get back and had a great time reminiscing on the incredible day of exploring Guatemala.</p>

<a href='https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/guatemala1/'><img width="150" height="150" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-92x92.jpeg 92w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-140x140.jpeg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>
<a href='https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/guatemala2/'><img width="150" height="150" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-92x92.jpeg 92w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-140x140.jpeg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>

]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
