<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>life guide &#8211; Andy Pande</title>
	<atom:link href="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/tag/life-guide/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/</link>
	<description>Web Development Enthusiast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 04:25:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Millennial&#8217;s Guide To Surviving a Long Distance Relationship</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/08/31/the-millennials-guide-to-surviving-a-long-distance-relationship/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/08/31/the-millennials-guide-to-surviving-a-long-distance-relationship/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 04:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bonding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long distance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long distance relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longdistance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longdistancerelationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millenial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=86</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ah, long distance relationships, how I loathe thee. If you have come upon this page, I can only imagine you...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, long distance relationships, how I loathe thee. If you have come upon this page, I can only imagine you are in the middle of a long distance relationship or about to embark on a long distance relationship adventure. Well, fear not &#8211; having survived (albeit with some bumps and bruises) a long distance relationship with a 17 hour time difference and 8998 miles of separation, I have an arsenal of tips to help you out.</p>
<p>First and foremost, before embarking on a long distance relationship &#8211; make sure you are truly committed to the person &#8211; SERIOUSLY &#8211; really make sure you are willing to put up with a lot of nights and days of feeling extremely lonely and frustrated. It is wise to have a conversation about this with your partner and make sure they are on the same page because it takes two wholly committed parties to make this wild adventure work.</p>
<p>Now, there are definitely things you can do to make it suck less, although mind you &#8211; it will SUCK &#8211; A LOT &#8211; LIKE A WHOLE LOT &#8211; at times. Here are a quick 5 tips to help you make it out alive.</p>
<ol>
<li>Get connected on as many apps as possible. Me and my girlfriend had a total of 11 different mediums we were communicating on during our long distance adventure. When the person you want to see most in the world can&#8217;t be physically there with you, it is a really great feeling to get constant updates from them via a plethora of apps and communication platforms. In my personal experience, listening to a song from a Spotify shared playlist that your partner added is the biggest mood booster and can help get you out of a crummy mood quickly.
<ul>
<li>Instagram</li>
<li>Facebook Messenger</li>
<li>Facebook</li>
<li>Snapchat</li>
<li>Spotify Shared Playlist</li>
<li>WhatsApp</li>
<li>Facetime</li>
<li>Texting</li>
<li>Email</li>
<li>Shared Photo Libraries on Icloud</li>
<li>Fitbit Challenges</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Read Books Together!!! &#8211; This should really be tip number 1 but I would recommend taking some time with your partner to talk about common interests and decide a book you are both interested in reading and start your own two person book club. This has a whole lot of benefits for your relationship, starting with a great discussion topic whenever you chat, to imagining your partner reading the book whenever you are reading, to helping you grow mentally rather than numbing your mind away until you see your SigO next. I have read other Long Distance preparation blogs that recommend watching Netflix shows or movies together but I found books were way more valuable for enriching your mind beyond just the few hours of the Netflix binge and the ideas help keep your mind distracted from the long distance annoyance for longer.</li>
<li>Always have your next meet-up planned as early as possible. One of the best and only ways to deal with the mental insanity of long distance is to know that you will have to only deal with it for 32 more days, then 31 more days, then 30 more days. Make sure to have a concrete date set for your meet-ups at all times AND before you leave a meet-up, make sure to plan the next one so you are not completely destroyed on your flight back. Bonus tip: Downloading countdown apps on your phone really helps and a countdown timer to look at every morning is a great reminder that you are getting closer to seeing your boo.</li>
<li>&#8220;Exercise is the most underutilized anti-depressant&#8221; This holds extremely true during long distance. During especially tough times, the endorphin rush from a good workout was the main saving grace to get through another night. My girlfriend and I even participated in a couple of <a href="https://www.shape.com/fitness/workouts/30-day-push-up-challenge">30 day pushup</a> or <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/79938962112500339/">30 day plank </a> challenges &#8211; which aside from being really good for you can help you feel connected with your partner knowing they are doing the same in another city as well. Even a nice walk or jog outside at times is the perfect way to get out of your funk, trust me &#8211; just try it!</li>
<li>Adapt. React. Readapt. Apt. For the non Micheal Scott fans out there, the final tip is to adapt and improve your relationship over time. One of the main things that my lady friend and I did was at the end of every meet-up, we would ask each other what was working well for the other person and what could be improved upon. For example, after feeling disconnected on the day-to-day happenings in each others lives, we decided that an improvement we could make is to send each other snapchats more often &#8211; even if they were of nonsensical happenings throughout the day. Having this conversation on the way to the airport whenever you are super mellow and emotional is also a good idea as it can help you snap out of the emotional anguish and get your rational brain back online to lay out a game plan to improve your relationship.</li>
<li>Bonus Tip: Memes. This post is titled a millennial guide after all. Me and my partner in crime LOVED sharing memes with each other during our LDR. From pictures of goats, to doggos, to Cardi B memes, we had a meme for everything to help brighten each other&#8217;s days. There was even a meme created about the immaturity of handling long distance with memes: <img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-87" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219.jpg" alt="IMG_1219" width="696" height="391" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219.jpg 696w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219-300x169.jpg 300w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219-600x337.jpg 600w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/img_1219-590x330.jpg 590w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" /></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hope this helps you brave long distance adventurers out there. Remember, it will all be worth it and you feel like like you have conquered a Herculean task when you are back in the same time zone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/08/31/the-millennials-guide-to-surviving-a-long-distance-relationship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
