<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Travel &#8211; Andy Pande</title>
	<atom:link href="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/category/travel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/</link>
	<description>Web Development Enthusiast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 04:16:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Singapore Solocation</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/02/singapore-solocation/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/02/singapore-solocation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 04:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=93</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just got back from a 4 day/4 night trip from Singapore and I am officially in love with this small...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Just got back from a 4 day/4 night trip from Singapore and I am officially in love with this small country in Southeast Asia. The first thing you notice in Singapore is just how clean and beautiful the country is. Next, you are blown away by the great diversity of the population and the tourists that are visiting the country. Driving through downtown on the way into the city, you cannot help but marvel at the majestic Marina Bay Sands, the Cloud Forest, the Singapore Flyer, and the SuperTree Grove. Pictures from Crazy Rich Asians flash in your head as you take in the immense wealth and potential the country holds. Immediately after visiting the country, I had to look up some history on how it has managed to prosper so well and I was shocked to find out that Singapore has only existed as an independent country for just over 50 years, only gaining independence in 1965! What’s even crazier is that the country has evolved from being a third world country when it was founded to a first world country in the matter of one generation, an astounding feat in itself. The country has also only had 3 prime ministers in it’s 54 years of independence and holds a one party meritocracy in it’s governing body.</p>
<p class="p1">My trip to Singapore was taken as a solo vacation &#8211; a solocation for short so I was hyper eager to soak in all the culture had to offer. Having grown up in India and visited a few countries in Southeast Asia, I have grown to expect a few surefire signs of being in Asia. In my mind upon arriving in Singapore, I expected there to be a homeless population easily visible even to tourists. Further, I expected there to be zero laws for drivers, and the make your own lane rule to govern how traffic flows. Finally, a subtle but noticeable fog/haziness was expected in the air from the pollution based on my previous experiences in Asia. Needless to say, none of this existed in Singapore. The homeless population is completely non-existent. Traffic flows without any honking and is managed beautifully. And the air, although very humid with up to 90% humidity, is very crisp and clean. Having stumped my beliefs of this actually being an Asian country, Singapore went above and beyond in blowing me away by just how safe it felt &#8211; even though I could not have looked any more like a tourist &#8211; by wearing a shirt with the Texas flag on it, an Astros ball cap and being glued to my phone for directions wherever I went, no part of Singapore felt unsafe. What was even cooler was how easy it was to use public transport in the city. On trip advisor, the number one rated attraction in Singapore is the Singapore Mass Rapid Transit (SMRT). Number one attraction in a city that holds the super tree grove, cloud forest, Marina Bay sands had me somewhat bewildered but after riding the train everywhere in the city for just 1-2 Singapore dollars per ride, I can see why it’s the best rated tourist attraction in the whole country.</p>
<p class="p1">My Singapore Solocation was split into two parts &#8211; part one was taking in the glitz and glamour of the country. This part consisted of trying delicious noms at the renowned Birds of a Feather restaurant. Next, I couldn’t leave the country without trying out some of the absolutely incredible cocktail bars. Operation Dagger was the first watering hole I visited where the bartenders made the most unique variation of an old fashioned that I have ever tried &#8211; this drink contained bee pollen and a dark chocolate twig. The bartenders could not have been nicer here and they hooked me up with a list of restaurants and other cocktail bars in the city to check out. Next on the treat yo self tour was checking out bar Manhattan in the Regent hotel. This bar is rated the best bar in Asia and the 3rd best bar in the world as of 2019 and boy did it ever hold up to that billing. The New York Sour was decadent and delicious, the waitstaff exemplary, and the ambiance and setting of the bar second to none. Having spent all of my next month’s pay check schmoozing, the 2nd part of my solocation involved checking out the more locals side of the country &#8211; and this part was even more delicious.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>New York Sour at the 3rd best bar in the world:</strong></span><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-96" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/unadjustednonraw_thumb_15c5.jpg" alt="UNADJUSTEDNONRAW_thumb_15c5.jpg" width="665" height="1182" /></p>
<p class="p1">While you can spend your whole vacation in Singapore visiting the top rated sites on Trip Advisor, you will be doing yourself a huge dis-service if you leave here without trying out the dozens of food hawker centers littered around the country. These hawker centers will get you a plate of authentic local food for under 5 Singapore Dollars. Plus, all varieties of food from Singaporean Laksa, to Malay dishes, to authentic Chinese food, to Indian delicacies to the most pungent but tasty desserts in South Asia made with Dorian can be bought for just a few dollars each. This was by far my favourite part of Singapore as the spices, flavours, ad aromas of these hawker centers were second to none &#8211; and my belly could not have been happier from the experience. There are some more touristy hawker centers like Newton food center that was depicted in Crazy Rich Asians and some more local friendly and tasty centers like the Maxwell food center but my list of the must try Hawker centers Food Recommendations are listed here:</p>
<p>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Trips/85571776</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>The original Katong Laksa &#8211; Absolute Must Try</strong></span><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-97" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/unadjustednonraw_thumb_15a4.jpg" alt="UNADJUSTEDNONRAW_thumb_15a4.jpg" width="768" height="1024" /></p>
<p class="p1">That about covers my overview of an unforgettable solocation to Singapore. For those of you interested, here’s a quick list of tourist attractions I believe are worth visiting, in order of their value for your time:</p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li1">Sentosa Island via cablecar</li>
<li class="li1">Singapore Zoo</li>
<li class="li1">Cloud Forest/Flower Garden &#8211; air conditioned</li>
<li class="li1">SuperTree Grove &#8211; daily shows at 7:45pm and 8:45pm</li>
<li class="li1">Marina Bay Sands</li>
</ol>
<p class="p1">Thanks for reading!</p>
<p class="p1">-AP</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2019/03/02/singapore-solocation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Antigua, Guatemala — The best kept secret in Central America</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 03:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[central america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guatemala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend getaway]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend, I had the pleasure of visiting Guatemala City and Antigua after finding out that flights were completely empty...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="a18a" class="graf graf--p graf-after--h3">This weekend, I had the pleasure of visiting Guatemala City and Antigua after finding out that flights were completely empty for non-revving down. Upon arriving with Guatemala City with no plans and no research, my first instinct and source of getting tips in the city was to ask the bus driver on the ride over to the hotel. Without skipping a beat, the bus driver recommended heading to Antigua, Guatemala for a day since I was only going to be in Guatemala for less than 48 hours. I made this my priority for the next morning after getting a good night of rest.</p>
<p id="1298" class="graf graf--p graf-after--p">After a hearty breakfast and a quick workout, I called an Uber to get over to Antigua from my hotel. Due to bad traffic, the Uber took ~2 hours to get there but I had an amazing ride with the driver who was learning how to speak English and was very candid in sharing his story, albeit in broken English, as well as answer any questions I had about Guatemala. Upon arriving in Antigua, I was blown away by what a beautiful &amp; quaint city it is. First thing I noticed was that the only way to commute around the city is on beautiful cobblestone streets. First stop upon arriving to Antigua was a delicious crepes restaurant named Luna De Meil. I chose this restaurant since it had over 900 reviews and a 4.5 star rating and let me tell you, it did not disappoint! The establishment had a beautiful terrace which complemented the perfect 70 degree weather well and a quick waitstaff to get a delicious chicken and spinach crepe and a banana mango smoothie. I was also able to use the free wifi there to scope out the best itinerary for the day. Post carbo-loading, the next stop was the Iglesias de la Merced- a beautiful church right next to Luna De Meil. After a quick 10 minute stroll through the church, the next stop was a quick 15 minute hike up to Cerro De La Cruz — which had an astounding view of the whole city of Antigua. It was a bit of a tough hike to get up to CDLC and I was a bit winded on a somewhat warm day but it was absolutely worth the amazing view in the end. After soaking in the view by hanging out up top and reading for an hour, I headed back down to visit the next stop on the adventure. According to Trip Advisor, another must do in Antigua was Convento de Las Capuchinas — which are ancient ruins from the 1200s. The ruins were absolutely gorgeous and it was very enlightening to see how nuns lived back in the day when Spain invaded Guatemala. Post embracing the ruins where there was a beautiful wedding taking place, the next stop was walking along the cobblestone streets towards the city’s central park. On the walk over, I couldn’t help but stop into the Museo Chocolate which was a sweet-tooths disneyworld with all kinds of chocolate to sample &amp; chocolate flavored rum — which meant I couldn’t leave without grabbing a couple chocolate bars and a few truffles. Getting back to the regularly scheduled activities led me to the plaza central park — which is a lively park in the middle of Antigua with all kinds of street vendors, live music, and an outdoor market on the weekends. I soaked in the ambiance and rested legs at the park for a quick 5 mintues then headed to Arco de Santa Catalina — which was rated the 2nd best attraction in all of Antigua according to TripAdvisor. The arch was beautiful but really not worthy of the 2nd best rating it was given online — perhaps it would be more enjoyable with a tour guide who could give history about the arch. After all the walking, it was time for grub! I had to consult with my trusty resource — TripAdvisor — and head to the #1 rated restaurant in the city  called &#8216;Porque No?&#8217; Going to school in Austin, I thought I had seen real hole in the wall food joints but this was another level of weird and eccentric. The walls were covered with signatures from everyone who had visited Porque No as well as eccentric art, shoes, and the random-est items your mind could conjure up. I was the first one in line at 6pm when they opened so I was able to get some quality time talking with the waitstaff and bartenders and owner &amp; they were some of the friendliest people I had ever met. They were super welcoming and gave me all the tips of where to go to really enjoy Antigua and even informed me a celebrity wedding had taken place just the weekend before in Antigua. I ordered a few Sangria’s(red and white) since I don’t discriminate with Sangria colors and then a grilled eggplant based on the bartenders recommendation. The drinks and the food were incredible and the whole meal cost under $20, what a treat! I was also able to pick the waitstaff’s brain for a great bar to check out on Saturday night and they recommended me to No Se — a Mezcal bar walking distance from Porque No which just happened to be rated the #1 bar in the city. Post having a happy belly, I headed to No Se and was blown away by what a cool and dank bar it was. The whole bar was only illuminated by candles and there was 3 separate rooms within the bar which all had a set of bartenders. It was a blast to hang out at the bar because again, the bartenders were super friendly and I was able to chat with a bartender from Italy who had moved to Guatemala after spending a couple of years in Australia before. A travel nomad that had me green with envy. While hanging at the bar, I also struck up with a friendly traveler next to me who was a real GOT (Goat of Traveling) who told me he is spending 6 months on each continent traveling around to really soak up the culture. Currently, he’s hanging out in Guatemala for 3 months for a volunteering opportunity for teaching English to super low income kids and was heading to explore the rest of Central America afterwards. It was super refreshing to meet someone who was so C’iest La Vie about really soaking up all opportunities that traveling have to offer and left me super inspired. I had a few Mezcal drinks at No Se while enjoying some great conversation before heading out since I had a 7am flight back to Dallas the next morning. I grabbed an Uber which luckily only took 40 minutes to get back and had a great time reminiscing on the incredible day of exploring Guatemala.</p>

<a href='https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/guatemala1/'><img width="150" height="150" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-92x92.jpeg 92w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala1-140x140.jpeg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>
<a href='https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/guatemala2/'><img width="150" height="150" src="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-92x92.jpeg 92w, https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/guatemala2-140x140.jpeg 140w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>

]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/30/antigua-guatemala%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8athe-best-kept-secret-in-central-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The quintessential list of all the best travel advice from an Airline Employee</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/16/the-quintessential-list-of-all-the-best-travel-advice-from-an-airline-employee/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/16/the-quintessential-list-of-all-the-best-travel-advice-from-an-airline-employee/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 04:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheapflights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheapvacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travelhacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traveltips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://andypandedotcom.wordpress.com/?p=62</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wanna travel for cheap? Here's all the tips for how to do it!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a post of my collection of all the extremely valuable resources and articles I have hoard&#8230;err&#8230;collected over time of working for an airline. Enjoy!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.frommers.com/blogs/arthur-frommer-online/blog_posts/it-matters-what-day-of-the-week-you-book-airfares-a-new-study" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cheapest Day to Book Airline Tickets</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bestproducts.com/fun-things-to-do/a1163/best-time-day-to-buy-airline-tickets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Best Time of Day to Buy Airline Tickets </a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.travelandleisure.com/trip-ideas/budget-travel/cheap-hotel-room-trick" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How to Book the Cheapest Hotels</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/best-travel-apps-in-2017-2017-8/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Best Apps to Make Travel Easier</a></li>
<li><a href="http://time.com/money/4895917/best-discount-luxury-hotel-booking-sites/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11 Websites to book Luxury Hotels for Cheap</a></li>
<li>Must have Flight Comparison Tools
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/flights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Flights</a></li>
<li><a href="https://skiplagged.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Skiplagged</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.momondo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Momondo</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.cntraveler.com/story/google-flights-hacks-that-save-you-time-and-money" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Flight Usage Hacks</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40430882/this-airplane-gadget-makes-flying-long-distances-in-coach-almost-bearable?partner=rss&amp;utm_campaign=rss+fastcompany&amp;utm_content=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_source=rss" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Airplane Gadget to Make Long Distance Flights in Coach Bearable</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/travelisfree/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook page that reports error fares</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurabegleybloom/2017/04/13/37-ways-to-game-the-airlines-how-to-get-free-flights-travel-upgrades-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">37 ways to game the airlines</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.travelchannel.com/roam-blog/news-deals/great-tips-on-booking-cheap-flights" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">8 Great Tips for booking cheap flights</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.popsci.com/how-to-book-cheapest-flights#page-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Use Tech and Tools to book cheapest flights possible</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2018/05/16/the-quintessential-list-of-all-the-best-travel-advice-from-an-airline-employee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Labor Day in Montana</title>
		<link>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2012/09/04/labor-day-in-montana/</link>
					<comments>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2012/09/04/labor-day-in-montana/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pande Saab]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 22:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andypande.wordpress.com/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Phew&#8230;writing this on Tuesday afternoon when returning to work after long and exciting 3 day weekend in Montana. Best highlights...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Phew&#8230;writing this on Tuesday afternoon when returning to work after long and exciting 3 day weekend in Montana. Best highlights of the trip for those who don&#8217;t wan&#8217;t to read the novel I&#8217;m about to write goes like this: Billings downtown is crazy, people are amazing and extremely friendly, Yellowstone is absolutely gorgeous with tons of Bison, Thest Bison are extremely&#8230;bold &amp; friendly and walk through middle of roads and even participate in mating season in front of park guests, &amp; finally Boat tours and Whitewater rafting in Yellowstone is incredible.</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;m going to try to break down the trip day by day in detail:</p>
<p>Friday(August 31st, 2012):</p>
<p>Left work around 3:30 to catch the 5:00 pm flight to Denver. As soon as landing in Denver, met up with Shivan in the United Club East. First experience in Airline club turned out to be exciting and downed 3 White Russians and a Blue Moon in about an hour. From there, got on flight from Denver to Billings, landing in Billings about 30 mins late around 10 pm. Got a rental car in Billings and went straight to Shivan&#8217;s hotel &#8211; Hilton garden Inn to put away bags and get ready to go out in Downtown Billings. Went to couple of brewery/bar deals in downtown which had cheap $2 beers and Casinos inside the bars. Me and Shivan chilled for a bit &amp; downed a brew or three while Shivan gave a tour of the cool bars around. Around 11:30, left to pick up Aneesh from the airport and came straight back to the bars downtown. Moved around to a couple bars until we settled on one bar that Shivan recommended. Met a local at the bar who was really chill and bought all 3 of us shots while giving us advice for what to do in Yellowstone and how to avoid bears. Soon after, went outside in this bar to find a group of young kids dressed in Jabbawockeez masks with a boombox set up on the street dancing and asking for tips. Saw these random kids dance with some of the bar patrons joining in for about 30 mins until Aneesh almost got in a fight and then bounced to the next bar. Next, checked out a placed called Rainbow Bar(no homo) that actually sold mini liquor bottles behind the bar&#8230;genius idea. After Rainbow bar, we were pretty drunk so headed back to the hotel to pass out. Passed out pretty soon after getting back while watching Harold and Kumar Christmas and got ready for &#8216;rents to arrive next morning around 10 and head over to Yellowstone.</p>
<p>Saturday(September 1st, 2012):</p>
<p>Woke up around 10:30 when rents arrived to the Hotel. Went down and had an amazing breakfast in the Hilton while chatting with the rents then headed out to grab groceries and head to Yellowstone. Took a super scenic route to Yellowstone through Bear Tooth Pass where we went up 10,000 feet in elevation and had an amazing lookout. (Insert Pic here) Kumud Mami was literally shitting her pants at this point because she is super afraid of heights and driving on a narrow road without railings did not help the cause. After the awesome drive and stopping every 10 mins for pictures, we ended up pulling up to a lookout lower on the peak that had a river you could wade into. Naturally, started throwing around the pigskin by the river and as soon as the games started, the football was in the water minutes later. Me and Ketan had to set up a rescue mission the river where we cornered the ball from both sides before it floated off into the rapids and was lost forever. Lucklly, we were able to retrieve the ball and minor hiccup aside, we continued on towards Yellowstone to check out some more scenic lookouts. After getting into the park, we stopped at a couple of spots to take some pictures, the coolest of which being an awesome waterfall which we had to hike down (&amp; up) 2 miles to get to see. INSERT FALLS PIC here. As soon as we came up from the falls, it started to pour rain and sleet so we all piled into the cars and headed for the Lake Lodge to check in. Upon arriving at the lodge, checked in right away and ran to the rooms to make some sandwiches since we had not eaten all day since breakfast. Chowed down on some sammies in the room and drank a couple brews then the bacchas headed for the lobby to grab some more drinks and check out the bar. By this time, we were all completely wiped out and the drink  prices were not exactly cheap, so me Aneesh and Ketan got a drink each and then headed back to the room right after. We were able to find out that BYOB was acceptable in the lobby so we were set on getting a bottle of liquor and lots of brews to the lobby when we returned the next night.</p>
<p>Sunday(9/2/12):</p>
<p>Woke up around 10 and headed to the Cafeteria in the lobby to grab some breakfast. Had a big hearty breakfast and set out for a day of adventuring the park. First stop was a quick 1 mile hike which went by a beach and lots of forest. Stopped at the beach to have a full photoshoot with jumping pics etc. and tossed around the pigskin. INSERT BEACH PICTURE HERE. From there, walked around and lazily finished the hike while taking waaay too many pictures along the way. Got back to the car and decided we were going to go check out Old Faithful &#8211; aka biggest and oldest geyser in the whole park. Otw to Old Faithful, stopped off at some smaller mud flats and geysers we saw along the way that lay on top of &#8216;Thin Crust&#8217; &#8211; which just made everyone hungrier since we had taken a long hike. After quick stop for geyser, we made another stop for Sandwiches lunch at a Picnic spot with next stop being Old Faith himself. Got to O.F. just in time for Geyser explosion and sat and watched the geyser bubble and shoot white hot steam and water all over everyone for a quick 5-10 mins. After this, had some time to kill so checked out Old Faithful Inn and hung out in there while grabbing some coffee and just exploring the gift shops and inn that were built in the 1800s. After chilling there for a bit, decided to head out to another awesome BlackSmith geyser that was on a list of &#8216;Top 10 things to Do in Yellowstone.&#8217; This geyser was awesome because it allowed you to get right up to the steam and be able to put your hand (illegally) in the hot water while getting real close. After getting burnt out on geysers, we decided to head to a different lookout point for the falls from Saturday so Shivan could get his picture perfect moment. Over there, grabbed a lot more pics of the falls, with a couple of hilarious anomaly pictures mixed in. Oversaturated with nature and pictures in general, we then decided to head to back to the hotel and get changed real quick so we could come back and grab dinner in the cafeteria before it closer. Got some delicious grub in the Caf before heading out to the lobby with beer and liquor bottles we had found earlier equipped in hand, ready to do it BIG that night. Hung out with rents and played cards for an hour or two while they got buzzed and were ready to pass out, then the real fun started. As soon as the rents bounced, started taking swigs straight out of the Yellowstone Bourbon bottle we had found earlier and moved onto more fun card games like Fuck the Dealer. Got somewhat inebriated after a couple games of FTD so we decided to head out to the porch to smoke a few cigars(also picked up earlier at Old Faithful Inn). When I said, this is when the fun started earlier&#8230;the fun actually did not start till this point. Within minutes of hanging outside and smoking cigars, we were approached by Bison which apparently had no problems roaming around the lodge chock full of people. The bison got literally within 10 feet of us, and we even saw a Bison get on it&#8217;s hind legs and go full out Sandusky onto another Bison(as mentioned in the summary). As if this wasn&#8217;t crazy enough, while smoking the cigars we saw some lights flashing across Yellowstone lake where we knew there was no inhabitable, which we later found out was an SOS call that we completely ignored. Following this ridiculous run of events, we didn&#8217;t know what to do but to go pound more bourbon and knock out our initial goal of finishing the bottle before the end of the night. This did not take long and we were soon done with the bourbon and moving onto beers from the cooler. We stayed at the lodge till about 1:30 when we were kicked out by the Security guard who had to close up shop, but we weren&#8217;t done drinking yet so we headed back to the porch to continue the shenanigans. It was at this point that we found out that the lights across the lake was an SOS since we saw police lights flashing in the same point where we had seen the SOS literally 20 minutes later. This led to the night being sworn in secrecy and not shared with anyone. The night eventually ended with us hanging out on the porch shooting the shit and having general drunk convos until we got too cold and decided to go pass out. Got to our cabins and passed out right away, completing our goal of knocking out the bottle of bourbon with no problems.</p>
<p>Note: Omitted from Saturday &#8211;</p>
<ul>
<li>Boat tour in the morning before the hike</li>
<li>Bison stampede before heading back to the lodge for dinner</li>
</ul>
<p>Monday (9/3/12):</p>
<p>Woke up lazily after getting pretty hammered the night before,  but suprisingly not hungover at all. Went to the lodge in the morning because Shivan had lost his camera(surpise surprise) and to check out. Camera found, headed out to lookout point next to the hotel to have some PB&amp;J breakfast sandwiches and check out the lodge hotel. Post hotel, went out to a trail we wanted to hike before heading out of Yellowstone. Trail was about 4 miles long and pretty amazing with lots of beautiful scenery, lakes and amazing lookouts over the canyon and waterfall(INSERT LOOKOUT PICTURE HERE). The hike finally ended at a stop called artist point where there was an amazing lookout of the famous waterfall where we hung out for a bit and took some more anomaly pics&#8230;Actually, took the best anomaly pic of them all (INSERT ANOMALY PIC HERE) before heading out on the road to get out to our whitewater rafting appointment. Before the whitewater tour, stopped real quick to grab some ice-cream and water refills, then headed out of yellowstone. Got to Montana Whitewater and quickly changed into swimming gear got a quick briefing before heading out onto the river and rapids. Rapids were pretty fun and whitewater tour overall was pretty awesome with a lot of level 3 &amp; 4 rapids but nothing as intense or lifethreatening as rapids in Alaska. After 3 hour whitewater tour, got recommendations from tour guide about best restaurants around Whitewater shop and got recommendation for a cool place called LightHouse cafe. Food at lighthouse cafe was incredible with some great Steak, Lamb, and Buffalo burgers and was well deserved as first full meal that wasn&#8217;t sandwiches. After great feast that included amazing dessert as well, started the 3 hour drive back to Billings, with Aneesh driving the whole way. Drive was fun because we hooked up Donald Glover standup to AUX and set up tablet on dashboard of car so we had hater vision while driving. Post drive, the Dattas checked into their hotel and Pandes headed back to our hotel from Friday night and passed out soon after checking out some pictures. Woke up next morning to take early 6 am flight back to Dallas via Denver and that was the end of an amazing Montana weekend!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://github.com/andypande/portfolio/2012/09/04/labor-day-in-montana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
